I have my system beep back!

Day 00391: Friday, 2016 April 01

I didn't work on job hunting today like I should have. However, I made major progress on include.d. In fact, the main goals of the working branch have been met and I can merge and release at any time now! That said, there are still other @todo items left, so I'm going to try finishing them before the release. I started working on completing these lesser tasks, and I've noticed that making visible progress is now a lot easier with the main goals accomplished. Before, every time that I'd complete a few tasks, a few more would come up. Now, the remaining tasks seem unencumbered by unnoticed and/or new tasks. When I finish a task, I actually make a step closer to having my code where I want it. I'm down to four @todo tags to deal with, only half of which are even code-related. Still, I've also run across bugs that I hadn't noticed before. After I think that I'm finished with all my @todo tag items, I should probably get back to writing up the debug scripts. It would be kind of stupid to release a version of include.d in which some of the classes and/or methods didn't pass even the most basic of checks. Some of the bugs I've found caused exceptions to be thrown or errors to be raised even with basic use.

Cyrus damaged his laptop by dropping it the other day, physically dislodging his headphone jack. He seems to make a habit of dropping his computer, but that's beside the point. After having done that, his speakers quit working. His theory is that the machine thinks that headphones are still plugged in, so the speakers were being kept off to accommodate, as most people don't want to use headphones and the speakers at the same time. He started changing his Audio Mixer settings though, and managed to get the speakers back on. Later, he offhandedly mentioned that his computer has been beeping since he got the speakers working, which he didn't like. Somehow, he'd activated the system beep using Audio Mixer! I asked him to show me what he'd done so I could replicate it, and it seems that he'd turned on just about every control toggle that he could find, and one of them happened to be labeled "beep", which he hadn't notice before. We were able to turn his beep off and mine on. I've really missed that beep, it used to alert me to all sorts of things. It seems to go off when I plug the laptop in, unplug it, or receive new emails, though I forget what all it did on thinkpad-x60s, on which it seems to be turned on by default. Additionally, it used to alert me to receiving messages on IRC, but I don't see an option to have it do that on WeeChat, so that functionality might be lost to me for now.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Blocking exit and non-exit Tor nodes

Day 00392: Saturday, 2016 April 02

My modem keeps giving out on me, which is incredibly annoying. It's been doing this over the past few days. Worse though, it somehow brings my Tor node down with it. Once Tor goes down, I can bring it back up, but it won't stay up, at least not if I bring it up with its correct configuration. Instead, I have to remove my IRC proxy hidden service from torrc file, start Tor, add the hidden service back to torrc, and run sudo killall -HUP tor to make Tor read and use the proper configuration. It's driving me nuts. If Tor is able to use the configuration I want, why isn't it able to start up with that configuration?

I haven't heard back from the Patreon people yet, so I decided to write another email, further explaining the problem:

Hello!

I've done more looking into this issue on my own. It seems to be due to the new obnoxious CAPTCHA frequency. It used to be that Patreon would force me to fill out a CAPTCHA every couple months or so. Now, Patreon requires a CAPTCHA every time that I visit the site. As a paying customer, this makes me very unhappy, but as the login issue was a bigger problem, I wrote about that first and was going to complain about the CAPTCHAs later. As it turns out though, your log in JavaScript is itself behind another CAPTCHA, one that can't be solved because it never gets seen.

I hate to be rude, but this really does need to be fixed. It isn't polite to bombard your paying customers with CAPTCHAs every time that they visit your site. Please, PLEASE fix this.

~ Yst Dawson

I hope that I didn't sound too rude, but their new policy of serving CAPTCHAs to Tor users is garbage.

Speaking of Tor users, the Geocaching website now thinks that my mother is a Tor user and is preventing her from logging her finds. There's no reason for this. Sure, we have a Tor relay at the house, but it's a non-exit node. Anyone that is connecting to their site from her IP address isn't a Tor user. Being that my mother is extremely against privacy and proxies, she blamed me, not the website. She doesn't know about my Tor node though, she only knows that I use proxies, so I was quickly able to get her to stop blaming me by showing her that, from her own Web browser, her IP address shows up as being one located in our city and owned by our ISP. Regardless, I don't need her looking into this any further, as she feels proxies, not those that block them, are the problem. Even if proxies were the problem, my node's not an exit, so blocking it doesn't block proxies; instead, it blocks people on the same network as a proxy. It's not an attack on anonymity, demanding that your users bow to you and tell you where they are. It's an attack on those that support anonymity, even if they are willing to give you, and only you, their IP address!

A while ago, I wrote to Geocaching about you blocking proxies being used to log finds. Although proxies are an important tool for fighting government surveillance, you took the pro-surveillance side and wouldn't fix the problem.

However now, you're blocking my mother, Dragon's Passion 4 Caching, from logging from her home connection. She doesn't use a proxy. Her home IP address is 97.82.100.91. Can you please do something to unblock her?

When I wrote to them about the issue with them blocking proxies, they mentioned being able to whitelist IP addresses, and they were willing to do it for me. It didn't help me, as my IP address changes every ten minutes, but I'm hoping that they'll do it for my mother. I dropped her name, as she has 13337 finds so far, so she's no small-time player. If they are willing to whitelist someone, they'll likely whitelist her. Furthermore, she's one of their paying members, and you don't want to block your customers.

I finished the upcoming version of include.d, but it was a good thing that I started working on the debug scripts again. I had tried to use \rawurlencode(). as a callback function for \preg_replace_callback(). \preg_replace_callback() passes an array to its callback, which I hadn't anticipated, and \rawurlencode() operates on strings. It was an easy enough fix, I just needed a wrapper function, but it seemed like overkill to build a function that simply takes an array and passes the first element to \rawurlencode(). I ended up instead creating a wrapper class that takes any callable during instantiation and wraps it for use with \preg_replace_callback(). Any string manipulation function that takes a single string as an argument and returns a string as output can be wrapped with an instance of this class. I also had a flash of inspiration, so I built a function and constant autoloader proof of concept. It works perfectly, aside from the fact that you can't use the standard function-calling and constant-checking syntax if you want to make use of the autoloader. It would be much nicer if this functionality were built into PHP the way that the class autoloading functionality is. I didn't get a chance to finish documenting this autoloading class though, so I'll have to do that at a later time.

There's still a lot of work to do before the debugging scripts are finished, but I think I'm going to try to get back to the job hunt tomorrow. I've made great progress on include.d over the past couple days, but include.d isn't my only responsibility, unfortunately.

Today, we went out gathering bullet shells again. While out, our mother briefed us on a couple updates. First, it seems that the CPR training tomorrow isn't CPR training, it's first aid training. Apparently, she'd told Cyrus and Vanessa, but had just assumed that I would somehow know. This changes things though. I'm not sure that there's a general "first aid certification", which means that there shouldn't be any need for my name anywhere; she won't be causing conflicts. Second, it seems that our mother was required to sign her work contract for next year today. Does that mean that we're staying in the city after all? I'm not sure, she might end up getting out of the contract somehow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I need some redundancy for my music storage.

Day 00393: Sunday, 2016 April 03

I didn't have a whole lot of time today, so I didn't finish documenting that function/constant autoloading class from yesterday. I did work on it long enough to hit a snag though. It seems that phpDocumentor doesn't like the PHP ... operator. The problem is that phpDocumentor tries to make sure that your code is syntactically valid. As PHP evolves, phpDocumentor's syntax validator falls behind. There's no reason for a documentation generator to validate syntax of code used within a function or method though. In any case, it seems that my documentation will appear broken until I finish building my own documentation parser. There's a workaround in which I can use different code to accomplish the same goal, and phpDocumentor likely won't complain about this workaround, but it's ugly. There are several reasons that the new ... operator was added to the language, and this is one of them.

I forget why I was glancing through his albums online, but I noticed that Mark With A C has renamed his album that was once known as "An Introduction To Marc With a C". It's now called An Introduction To Marc With a C (FREE!). What's with that? I thought that all his albums were free. Furthermore, I thought that all but his newest three were gratis, which is what he probably meant by the word. Looking through his albums though, several that previously were available gratis (with an optional payment to him) now have a price tag. There's nothing wrong with trying to make more money like this as long as he continues to use a free license, and so far, he is doing that. I think that it represents a shift in attitude though. He told me that the reason that his work is available gratis is that he didn't like that some people couldn't afford it, and in particular, one fan had practically begged him for a copy of some of his work. Now, it seems that money is a bit more important. Of course, I'll continue to support him (especially after I finally find a job), but it's interesting to notice this shift.

Seeing as the title of that album has changed, it's kind of like a different album, but with all the same songs. Bandcamp doesn't see it that way, and offers me access to the new version instead of the old one on my purchases pages, so I downloaded the new version to put on my mobile alongside the old version. I'm kind of silly like that sometimes. Because I was working with music on the mobile anyway and had a small unknown amount of time to kill, I started trying to sort the music in the directory structure the same way as the mobile sorts it in the music player. I already had it pretty close, but there were a few things out of place. I went through the list of albums to ensure that it matched my file tree, and found a strange extra album: a glitchy copy of Crawford Street. This album contained three copies of every song that the regular copy contained and somehow hadn't been merged with the main album. Of course, this album wasn't showing up anywhere in the directory tree of my SD card. I finally figured out that there were broken files pertaining to this album in the lost+found directory, though I never could see them. Additionally, and this is the crazy part, there were three lost+found directories! Something was clearly wrong. I tried to delete these directories, but I could only delete one of them, and after that, Thunar became unable to display the contents of my SD card at all. I could still see the files on the command line, but rm was unable to remove the offensive directories. I never could figure out how to get the file system working correctly, even with fsck, so I ended up deleting everything and putting the files back on, using another copy from my laptop. This got me thinking though. I need to find somewhere safe to stash my files in case of problems. I don't have my music on my laptop, at least not sorted into directories based on license like I do on my external hard drive. If I lose those archive files, along with the license information that they show me based on where I put them in the file tree, I have to delete them across all my electronic devices if I'm unable to get the archives and their license information back. After all, without license terms, they are effectively nonfree. I don't have space for the archives on my laptop or on my mobile. I ended up reformatting that USB drive that I bought from Professor Shyguy. It'll now act as one more place to stash a copy of my music files. I might end up storing more there at some point, such as my encrypted password database file, but I'm less worried about losing that. It's small enough that I can stash copies of it in several places. If possible, I'd like to find an off-site place to back my music archives up to though, two copies seems like too few.

Speaking of the USB drive, it seems that that USB drive now comes with a copy of Instrumentation, which it didn't before. As an early adopter, I guess I missed out on that. Then again though, I also paid $20 USD less because I bought it early, so there's that.

The Geocaching people haven't written back yet. However, my mother is no longer having issues on their site. Did I contact them prematurely? The issue may have resolved itself somehow. I'd rather have contacted them prematurely and look foolish than have waited and the problem not sort itself out quickly though. I don't need my mother to shut down me and my Tor node, so I'd like to keep any proxy-related issues out of her view if at all possible. Making waves is often good, but there is a time and a place for it, and this isn't it.

It seems that last night, my mother found out that there were a couple of issues with the first aid training today. As usual, she somehow assumed that I'd know, even though she never told me. Yet she says that I'm the one that warps reality. Getting back on topic though, the training had a total of only twelve open spots, so we didn't know if there would be space for us left. It was also for adults only, so Vanessa couldn't go at all, even if there was space left. Not wanting to leave her out, the plan to go there was canceled. We instead went to the beach, then went to the hills to pick up bullet shells.

Tomorrow, I hope to be more productive than I was today. It's true that I didn't have a whole lot of time to spend being productive today, but what little time that I did have, I spent not searching for a job when I could have. I didn't even finish any non-job-related tasks. I started documenting that one class, but I didn't have time to finish because I got distracted by the Marc With a C album name change. I started fixing the sorting of my music, but I ended up having to replace a broken file system instead.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mother is just being vindictive!

Day 00394: Monday, 2016 April 04

While I formatted my Professor Shyguy USB drive yesterday, I didn't move any of the files to it until today. Now that I've tried actually adding files to the USB drive, I've found that the thing doesn't work! Every time that I remove the drive from newdawn and plug it back in, the file system is corrupted. It started out only corrupting when I added files, but bad went to worse quickly. It doesn't matter if I add files or not, the file system becomes corrupt. With much help from people in #Debian, I found a pattern though. The drive only corrupts when the file system on the drive isn't FAT32. Ugh, I hate FAT32. In addition to the needless fragmentation and being prone to file system breakage, FAT uses file names that are case-insensitive and and severely limit uses of non-alphanumeric, ASCII-range characters. Using a FAT file system, I'll be able to back some files up, such as my compressed music archives, but I won't be able to store an extracted and organized copy of my music for easy transfer to a device that I want to play music on. I planned to spend very little time with files today, simply setting up the transfer and letting it complete on its own, but I ended up debugging this all day. In the end, I *still* didn't manage to get the files backed up either! So much for working on the job hunt today. I'll get the files transfered tomorrow.

While working on the USB drive today, I noticed something strange. This "32GB" USB drive is actually a 64GB drive! At first, I thought that this was an oversight by Professor Shyguy, but looking at the store page again, it seems that it's called a 32GB in the title, but within the body text, it's mentioned as being a 64GB drive. Strange.

I've figured out why my Tor is going down, at least in part. It seems to go down when my modem goes down, which had been confusing to me before, but it turns out that it has something to do with Tor's restarting. I'm not sure why Tor is restarting, but if it restarts while the modem is down, my DNS server is unable to resolve DNS records, so Tor crashes because of "unparseable" addresses to forward to. If Tor would quit restarting, the problem would go away. Likewise, if the modem would quit failing, there wouldn't be an issue. One thing that still confuses me though is that once Tor goes down because it can't resolve an address, it fails to reperform the DNS lookup once I try restarting Tor with DNS services back up.

Our mother took us to see some old military base ruins today. While the ruins were interesting, what's more interesting was her admission while there. She had been there before, but thought that the ruins were just barely not visible from the main road. She also thought that there was only one old room. Once we made it there, we saw that the ruins were way down a trail, quite a ways from the road, and there were three rooms. We didn't say anything about that of course, but she admitted that her memory is often bad! Somehow though, although she knows that her memory is poor, she'll argue to the death that she remembers correctly about things and we don't. On the way home, Vanessa was trying to get our mother to go on a walk with her, but our mother didn't want to go. Vanessa didn't want to go without our mother, so she gave up on going out. Or mother started acting like she didn't understand why Vanessa no longer wanted to go on the walk, and started telling her off. I explained the situation, so our mother told me off! She them proceeded to explain that she wanted Vanessa to explain the obvious to her. She's just being vindictive to Vanessa! Our mother complains that Vanessa is afraid to talk to people, but our mother herself is a big cause of it! We all know this, but it seems that our mother is doing it intentionally. I'm appalled. Most of the misunderstandings between Vanessa and our mother probably aren't misunderstandings at all, but deliberate attacks from our mother.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm employed!

Day 00395: Tuesday, 2016 April 05

It turns out that my Professor Shyguy USB drive doesn't actually work when using FAT32 either! The file system doesn't look like it corrupts, but files usually become invisible, taking up space on the drive, but lacking file names so that they can't be reached! This is highly frustrating. It gets me thinking though. This is the first time that I tried to write to the drive. Furthermore, when I received the device, it didn't contain all the files that I expected it to. Some albums were on the drive in MP3 format only, while some albums were missing entirely. One album was only partially included! What if the drive was broken from the start? Maybe the unexpected lack of files was because the files had gone missing. The drive could have been broken before being shipped, or it might have gotten damaged in the mail somehow. In either case, I need to contact Professor Shyguy about the problem. I don't need a replacement USB drive, but I'd like to get him to email me the files that are supposed to be on the drive. I plan to rebuy the main files from his Bandcamp account eventually to get them listed on my account, but I don't know if any of the USB-drive-only files were lost.

I didn't work on the job hunt today, as being paranoid, I wanted to make sure my music was backed up. I set newdawn aside so it wouldn't get bumped while it copied the files from my external hard drive, which is finicky about the cable being bumped sometimes, to cepo, which is reached over two Wi-Fi hops from newdawn. Needless to say, it was a slow process and took all day to complete! I decided to just take the day off to try to relax and get over the stress of dealing with the failing drive. That didn't last too long though, as the temp agency contacted me about a job!

The temp agency got word that a position that I had previously been turned down for through them had reopened, and they were giving me the chance to fill it! I needed to come in to fill out some forms and allow them to copy my photo ID and either my Social Security card or my birth certificate. They also asked me to bring my bank account information to set up direct deposit. I didn't realize that employers could use a birth certificate in place of a Social Security card, but I really didn't want to try to find my birth certificate, as newdawn was resting on top of my filing box. I'd risk bumping the external hard drive's cord too much and interrupting the file transfer if I moved the laptop somewhere else, so I went with the Social Security card. I'll keep this in mind for next time though, if given the option. Once I made it to the temp agency, I found that while I'd dug out my Social Security, I'd left it at home instead of bringing it! I ended up having to return later to bring it over. On the first visit though, I learned more about the job. It seems that I'll be doing something with conveyor belts and plastic bottles. It's a graveyard shift position, and the job will only last somewhere from a few weeks to a few months. It's really short-term, but it's a paying job! Also while there, they popped a surprise drug test on me. The only drug that I sometimes take is caffeine, which is found in chocolate and tea. Other than that, I'm clean, so I obviously passed the test. I thought that I'd need to wait for the results, but it turns out that they gave me my negative result before I left. Also, the temp agency representative said that my first one or two pay checks might end up coming via paper mail instead of direct deposit, as it takes a while for the bank (or in my case, credit union) to approve it. It sounds like I might have been able to avoid direct deposit! I'd be more upset about being roped into direct deposit needlessly, but I'm just happy to be employed for a while. The temp agency representative emailed me a pair of PDF files that total thirty-nine pages and act as a sort of employee manual. I don't have time to read them tonight though, I'll probably start reading them tomorrow.

On the way home, I cut through the local forest park, as there's an entrance near the temp agency. On the way to the temp agency, I'd asked if a particular street was in a particular direction, as I was trying to take a shorter route than usual, and had been directed to instead cut through the forest, so taking a similar path back seemed reasonable. I found an even better path through though! Not only is there an entrance right near the temp agency, there's one on the far end of my street!

When I told my mother about the job, she got weird. She says that it's leven kilometers away and will be a two and a half hour walk. I don't have much of a choice though, it's not like I've gotten any other job offers. She offered me a ride there, though not back, as she'll be at work when I need to return home. I of course declined, as there's a reason that I don't drive myself. Her driving me is as bad as me driving myself, and I have quite a bit of stamina. I can make the trip on foot just fine. However, upon declining, her offer changed and became an order. She insists that she will be driving me there daily. This is frustrating. While I can't afford to turn down this job, if I'd know that she was going to do this, I probably would have declined the job anyway. She blames part of her carbon footprint on me, but this is a prime example of why her argument is invalid. I don't want the ride, but she's insisting on it. Her carbon footprint is hers and hers alone.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Only three hours of sleep

Day 00396: Wednesday, 2016 April 06

Before heading to work last light, I made sure that all the music on my mobile was sorted at least into the correct directories, though I didn't have time to make sure that all the file names were correct. Bad idea. I should have gotten some rest instead. By the end of my shift, I was somewhat delirious from exhaustion.

On the way there, I found two very good facts. First, the walk home sends me right past a distant grocery store that sells vegan bread. Whenever we're low, I can pick some up on the way home! Second, my mother said that she doesn't know how long she'll be able to continue dropping me off at work with how late I need to be there. Perfect! I never wanted her to drop me off anyway, She just insisted, and it's usually best not to argue with her when she gets like that.

I found the work site to be very informal. I brought my photo ID and the paperwork that the temp agency had given me thinking that I'd need to prove that I was supposed to be there, but neither was needed. They just sort of let me in. Their old time clock doesn't function the same way as the last old time clock that I used did. The last one stamped your time card if you inserted your card all the way to the back. Instead, this one stamps your card when you hit the button on the top. I spent the day putting together sets of those plastic tree protectors that are used to keep deer from eating planted saplings. It turns out that those things are made from biodegradable plastic, too! One of the people that was helping me learn how to do it the easy way had to keep giving me the same tips because I couldn't take it all in at once. I had to focus on one tip at a time until I finally had it. It's very simple work after a while. One sucky part of the job is the unpaid meal break. Seeing as I had not gotten any sleep, it was helpful this time, but normally, if I'm going to be stuck there, I want to be paid for it, even if that means having to work instead of break. I know that the unpaid meal break is required by law, but my last employer let people get away with not taking the meal break if they wanted to stay clocked in, in which case they still got the regular paid ten-minute breaks.

I noticed a sign in the break room that says that anyone that doesn't already have health insurance is required to participate in the company insurance plan, which they must pay for. This is ridiculous! Surely this is some ploy to force some employees to have to give back some of their hard-earned money to the employer. I went to ask what I needed to to to get out of the company insurance plan, as I already have insurance and don't want to give up extra money needlessly, but it seems that the rule doesn't apply to people in temporary positions such as mine.

My mother wanted me to get a background check through her school so that I'd be able to ride her school bus part way home. FOr the next while, her students are taking field trips to the pool nearish to my work. I'd still have to walk about an hour to get to the bus, assuming I'm fast enough, and the bus wouldn't get me all the way home, but it'd be something. I really didn't want to hand over my Social Security number to the school, which is required for the background check, but I did it anyway. If I could save an hour of walking without causing further fossil fuel usage (as the bus wouldn't be making any extra stops for me), it might be worth it. The school's form is moronic though. First, it disallows pasting. I'm not going to read and type my Social Security number just because some stupid website won't allow me to paste it from my encrypted password database. I ended up filling it with autotype. Apparently, I no longer have the add-on installed that prevents moronic websites from disabling the paste feature. It also insisted that I provide a driver license number. I don't have a driver's license, but the form wouldn't allow me to leave this field blank. It allowed me to use the string "none" though. Maybe I should have instead used the string "I don't have a driver license.".

Speaking of buses, I haven't seen a single bus stop in Coos Bay or North Bend. Do we not have public transportation here?

New estimates suggest that the walk is over nineteen kilometers. It took me three and a half hours to walk home. Assuming that I walk to and from work and I manage to get eight hours of sleep, I would have time for nothing besides work, walking, and sleep. I wouldn't even get any rest periods between walking and working. Of course, that's only assuming that I actually get enough sleep. Upon returning home, my body wouldn't allow me to sleep more than three hours. I am so very tired.

I received a letter from my dentist's office stating that they had changed my dental care provider from their Coos Bay office to their North Bend office. Furthermore, they said that for all appointments, I need to bring my insurance card and my photo ID. I would have brought the insurance card, but left the photo ID behind, so this was an informative letter despite my already knowing about the switch.

I took a look at my bicycle, trying to get it in working order to speed my commute. The tires are flat on one bike and the wheels are bent on the other. I tried inflating the tires of the one bike, but I couldn't get the pump working. Questioning whether it was even the right pump, I tried connecting it to the tires of the bike with inflated tires. If I could get it to let air out, it was probably the right pump. In the process though, the pump got stuck. Getting it off damaged the tire, ripping the valve stem off entirely. Lovely. That's not really fixable, and that might have been the inner tube that I had bought to fix that flat last time. I've never even gotten to ride on that inner tube, or if I did, it wasn't for long. I quickly found that the wheel had been bent after installing that inner tube. I went back to working on the bike with flat tires, but the pump started leaking. It took a while, but I fixed the pump, then actually managed to inflate the tires. I let the bike stand there for over an hour to see if the tires would hold air, as I suspected that they didn't. The person that sold us the bike said that he thought that the tires could hold air, but I doubted that even at the time. If they could hold air, it would mean that someone had intentionally let the air out at some point. Why would they do that? The most reasonable explanation was that the tires were in fact damaged and had gone flat of their own accord. As expected, the tires were differing levels of flat when I came back. One was entirely empty, the other was too flat to ride, but still had some pressure in it. On the way home tomorrow, I planned to pick up a pair of 26 inch by 175 inch inner tubes, though later events caused me to cancel that plan.

Apparently, we have garter snakes in the area. I found one lying across the cement walkway leading up to the house. I walked somewhat near it to get past, but it didn't seem to care enough to flee.

My modem continues to fail and Tor continues to react to the failure by shutting down. I think that I can fix the issue by using IP addresses in the configuration file instead of domain names. I strongly believe that the problem is caused by Tor's choice to restart, seemingly randomly, then attempting DNS lookups when local DNS services are unable to reach remote DNS services for the lookup on non-//test. names. With IP addresses, there's nothing to look up. The problem with switching to IP addresses though is that I can't remember which IP address is which when looking at the configuration file, and additionally, my hidden service configuration parser that creates a list of available hidden service ports will no longer output human-readable domain names, instead outputting long lists of IP addresses. When I have the time and energy, I need to create a new tool, one that takes a domain-based hidden service configuration block, performs the necessary DNS lookups, and outputs a new IP address-based hidden service block. I can run that script while DNS services are available, then not have to worry about Tor's failing attempts to resolve DNS records later. I'd work on the tool now, but I can't write software in my current state.

I was going to contact Professor Shyguy about the USB drive today, but I don't think my mind is clear enough to make that a good idea right now. With only three hours of sleep, I might not phrase things as well as I really should.

I'm very tired. And now I need to go back to work. These next few months are going to be a beast, and I am not looking forward to them. Tomorrow might be better than today though. I didn't really have anything portable that I could make a meal of, so for lunch, I brought two cans of vegetables. That's all. I ended up eating only one of the cans, as a second can of vegetables wasn't appetizing. On the way home though, I picked up some bread, so tomorrow, I'll have sandwiches at work.

My mother said that she's taking the day off of work tomorrow to head to Springfield to get her favorite tax preparers to file her taxes for her. She also said that she'd pick me up after work. As hypocritical as it makes me feel to want the ride, it'll be a relief not having to walk that distance again after an eight and a half hour shift after having only had three hours of sleep.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Jury summons

Day 00397: Thursday, 2016 April 07

Yesterday on the way home, I found a key holder, along with a strip of paper containing three signatures and a plastic bag containing a pencil. No doubt, this was a dismantled Geocache, so I put it back together and hid it where I thought that it was supposed to go: behind the nearby rock wall. I offhandedly mentioned it to my mother, so she wanted to see it. We couldn't find the rock wall though. I'll have to keep an eye out for it and take note of the street name. It turns out that it was never her intention to take me to Springfield with her, she was just picking me up because she had the day off, then dropping me off at home and heading out.

I was thinking that my job in the extrusion room was too loud and that it was preventing the sort of conversation that could lead to on-the-job friendships. While I can stand the noise level, one person even wears ear plugs! I wouldn't say that I'm lonely, but one thing that I'd been looking forward to in becoming employed was the in-person human interaction. Just as I had started thinking about that though, people started talking. Earplug guy wasn't very talkative, most likely because he couldn't really hear people very well, but I was able to speak with some of my other coworkers for a while. To try to start a conversation with the boss, I mentioned that after putting several of the sapling protectors inside each other as we were doing, they looked kind of like a humidifier filter, which worked. The boss seems like a pretty nice guy.

At some point near the beginning of the shift, the boss offered me a stool and a tip. Yesterday, I ended up going to work at about the time I usually go to bed. I had had a full night of sleep, but my shift ended after I would have usually gotten up, so I was feeling more and more out of it as my shift dragged on. This time, I'd slept more recently, so I wasn't passing the twenty-four hour mark, but I'd only slept for three hours. I'm not sure if the more recent sleep had been better, despite not being long enough, or if it was the stool that helped, but today's shift was much more tolerable. Yesterday, I seemed to have taken the dead skin off my hands while working, as today, I was starting to hit live skin. Not fun. The boss said that you can use masking take to cover the spots on your hands that get rubbed raw though, preventing damage to your skin. It worked pretty well! I think that I should get a pair of gloves to bring to work though. They'd be easier to put on and take off than the tape and would be reusable.

The extruder responsible for the sapling protectors started malfunctioning, resulting in only broken protectors being produced. While the boss was diagnosing and repairing the machine, we couldn't continue what we had been doing. Instead, the person I was working with helped the boss with the extruder while I ended up working with two other extruders. One extruder was slow, pushing out long tubes of unknown purpose, having a similar hole pattern as the sapling protectors, only smaller. The second extruder produced small bags, again with a similar hole pattern. While working the sapling protector extruder is a two-person job because of how quickly the protectors come out, working both of the other extruders, along with a second bag extruder, is a one-person job with wait time in between doing things. The person that had previously been doing that job continued to work the one bag extruder while I worked the other bag extruder and the strange tube extruder, leaving even more wait time between doing things for both of us. The sapling protector extruder was fixed soon enough though, so we were able to get back to being more productive.

The boss said that I could choose when I took my lunch break, and that all I had to do was let him know before I left. I considered not even taking a lunch break and just working through the whole shift straight. That would have allowed me to remain on the clock for an extra half hour. It's stupid that I have to be in the area, but off the clock, for half an hour. After a few minutes, I thought better of that plan though. One of two things would happen if I stayed on the clock. Either I would be accused of taking the lunch break but failing to clock off or the boss would get in trouble for not making sure that all the employees got their law-mandated lunch breaks. If accused of not clocking out, I might not get paid for that time anyway, and I'd be in trouble. If the boss was accused instead, he'd be taking heat for what wasn't his fault. He seems very nice, I'd rather not cause him problems. With that in mind, I decided instead to wait until I had only two and a half hours left until my shift ended, take the lunch break, and come back with only two hours left to work. If I did that, I'd have the bulk of my shift out of the way and the rest should be easy to finish. However, it turned out not to matter anyway. Half an hour before I planned to take my lunch, the boss sent me out on lunch himself. No one would have been in trouble anyway.

From the sound of it, my temporary position with the company exists because of unexpected forest fires. Normally, the forestry companies place their orders far in advance, giving the company time to produce their product at a reasonable pace, stockpile it, and fill the order on time once enough are produced. However, because of these fires, the forestry company or companies have had to increase their orders. In order to fill the order or orders on time, speed was increased and temporary jobs, including my own, were created.

My job involves putting together sets of ten sapling protectors, so there's a lot of counting to ten. Today, I realized that I could be using that time to practice counting in Esperanto. I started continuously counting them, not resetting to "nulo" between sets. I made it to about "cent dek sep", but "cent dek" sounds too much like "sepdek", so between the noise of the machines, my tiredness, and conversations, I started confusing myself. I ended up just counting to "cent" repeatedly and resetting to "nulo".

My boss offered me a ride to the mall, as he was already headed there. That mall is just down the street from my house! However, my mother had already said that she was picking me up, so I declined. I briefly considered emailing her to call off the ride, but she had wanted me to show here where that key holder that I mentioned earlier was, so I did need to meet up with her. He says that he frequently visits that mall though, so if I ever want a ride, I can let him know. Still, I have no way to know if he's headed there without potentially causing him to go there, so I can't actually take him up on that offer.

My body didn't want to sleep today either, despite being tired. It sort of complied anyway though. I was able to take a three-hour nap, at which point I woke back up, then took another three-hour nap right away. It's not a full night's sleep, but it's better than I've had. Tomorrow should be easier than today or yesterday was.

I've decided that my request to Professor Shyguy is a strange one. Basically, the physical product that I purchased arrived broken, but I don't want a replacement. (Well, I do want a replacement, but I'm going to suck it up and not try to get one.) Instead, I'm assuming that the data contained is similarly broken, and I want him to email me a copy of what the data should be. With that goal in mind, I considered whether withholding some of the details of the situation might be a more effective strategy than explaining the situation in-depth. Basically, I could explain that I tried writing to the USB drive, at which point the thing started acting wonky and lost all the date, including the music, then ask if he could email a copy of the music. Technically, that story is true. I did attempt to write to the USB drive, at which point it lost the music files along with the new data. The fact that I had a backup of what might not have been everything is irrelevant. I ended up deciding against this plan though. A better plan is to make a list of exactly what was and wasn't on the USB drive when it arrived, explain the data loss and that I think that the drive arrived broken considering that this was the first time that I tried writing to it and the fact that files seemed to have been missing from the start, and ask if there actually were missing files. Doing that would be the most honest way to try to insure that I have the files that were supposed to come on the drive.

Checking the mail today, I found a jury summons for me. That's all well and good, but the included instructions demand that I call a particular telephone number on a particular date to find out if I'm actually going to be serving on a jury. If chosen, it is then demanded that I telephone the number every day during a certain period of time. No options were provided for people without telephone service. This is ridiculous! I am very angry. There is no legal requirement that citizens have telephone service, so there can't be a legal requirement that I call that number or any other. They can't just assume that everyone is able to reach them via telephone. It's bad enough when optional services make such assumptions, but when legally-required processes make this assumption, it is unacceptable. Additionally, the jury that they want me to serve on is in Coquille, which is at least eight hours away on foot. It's not really feasible for me to serve on this jury. The jury summons letter says that if it is a transportation hardship for me to serve, I may include a note with the required filled questionnaire explaining my situation. When I send the questionnaire tomorrow, I will include this note (I've redacted the "user" portion of the email address that I will include in the note for privacy):

I am a pedestrian in Coos Bay, I don't drive. If you check my DMV record, you can see that I don't even have a driver license. Walking to Coquille would take an estimated eight hours, and that's only one way. While I'd love to serve on a jury, serving on a jury in Coquille isn't really feasible for me. If you have a trial in Coos Bay or North Bend that I could be a jury member for, that would be much more feasible.

Additionally, I don't have telephone service. I haven't had telephone service for over a year now. I can't call that telephone number that your jury summons letter says that I must call to find out if I have been chosen. There is no legal requirement that citizens have telephone service, so you cannot require that I do. If you want me to serve on a jury, you will need to provide another way for me to know if I have been chosen. If you post this information online, I can check it, as I do have Internet service. Alternatively, I'm available via email at <mailto:[REDACTED]@y.st> and via postal mail at the mailing address specified on the questionnaire provided with this letter.

On April 29, the date that it is demanded that I call and listen to the jury duty instructions recording, I will find some public place and get the people there to lend me a telephone. If the court people aren't going to be reasonable, I don't want to get in trouble over it. I also don't need the stress of not knowing if I was chosen and not knowing if I'm skipping court case that I'm expected to participate in. If you're curious, and if you buy into the idiotic telephone number system, I am juror number 158.

Once I got out of bed, I needed to get to the store to buy the inner tubes that I need for my bicycle. I asked my mother if she wanted me to pick anything up while I was at the store before I headed out, but that was a mistake. She said to wait until she got home from Springfield and she'd drive me there. The whole point of fixing up the bicycle is to avoid driving! Additionally, it seems that she's not cool with using the bicycle to get out of her giving me rides to work, even though she's losing sleep to give me these rides. Because she didn't get home before dark and I wasn't going to be able to ride the bicycle to work anyway, only from work, I ended up not getting the inner tubes installed. It's too hard to try to get them put on in the dark and with too little gain. I'll have to walk home tomorrow instead of riding home, but that's fine.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Speaking with Professor Shyguy about lost data

Day 00398: Friday, 2016 April 08

On the way to work, I located that rock wall with the dismantled Geocache. It turned out to be one that my mother had already found years ago, but at least we don't have to look for the wall any further.

At work, I decided to push my counting in Esperanto a bit further. If I could get to "cent dudek", I'd be past the spot where the numbers sounded too similar to lower numbers. I ended up making it all the way to "sepcent kvindek", but then I decided to stop. It was starting to require too much concentration just to remember where I was. Work is hard enough, I don't need to be making it needlessly harder. I ended up instead repeatedly reciting the digits "nulo" through "naŭ". I noticed that I was much more alert today than I've been over the past couple days, no doubt because I got a bit more sleep yesterday. I don't have that luxury today though, so I'll probably be tired again at work tomorrow. I've also noticed that since the first time I woke up after my first shift, I've had a kink in my back that won't go away. Hopefully that'll work itself out soon.

On my break, I started messing around with the vending machine in the break room. You can insert one-dollar bills into it, then tell it that you changed your mind, at which point it'll spit out four quarters. It doesn't take other bill denominations though. I'm going to bring a bunch of stamped one-dollar bills tomorrow just to put them into circulation.

One of my coworkers knows about the net neutrality issue! It feels like there are too few people that even know what's going on, let alone care about it. If net neutrality is taken away, I think a lot of people are going to learn the truth real quickly and start making a fuss, but by then, it'll be too late. My coworker also seems to be aware of Bitcoin (he brought it up, not me), though he doesn't actually use it. At some point, I should probably figure out what I need to do to start using Bitcoin, but it'll be a pain because of the huge block chain. The problem's only going to get worse as time goes on.

My boss mentioned that the sapling protectors can be a bit rough on one's hands, so I said that I'd been thinking about getting some gloves because of that. He said that I'd probably want fingerless gloves so that I'd still be able to grip the protectors, though I fear that fingerless gloves won't be protective enough. The tips of my pinkies are a couple of the focal points of the damage. A bit later, he brought me a pair of gloves to borrow! They weren't fingerless, so they offered pretty good protection, but he was right. Despite the fact that the gloves were covered in grip-aiding bumps, I couldn't grip the protectors as well, so they slowed me down.

We finished working with the sapling protectors of the size we started with and moved on to making some taller ones. Apparently, people sometimes order them as tall as one and a half meters feet, those these ones weren't that tall. I'm not sure what kind of tree is still thin enough to need protection from deer by the time it gets to a height of one and a half meters though. I love that I live in an area where someone would even order this many sapling protectors. The area just supports plant life so well! If you step outside and look around, you can see hundreds of trees without even searching.

The extruder was running at a set speed, so when the cutter's settings were changed to allow bigger sapling protectors, less of them came out. I wasn't needed on that machine any more, as less people were required at the slower pace. Instead, I started working with the other extruders and cutters. I ran both of the bag machines and the machine that produced the long, strange tubes from yesterday. It was pretty easy work, I could sort of relax while doing it. The strange tube machine only kicked out a tube every once in a while, and it wasn't urgent that the tubes be handled, so I could ignore it when something more pressing was going on. One bag machine always stopped when it had a full set of bags, so it needed to be kept under watch, so that the bags could be taken, the machine restarted, then the bags wrapped up. Otherwise, the machine would not be running as much as it could be. The other bag machine endlessly spat out bags, keeping a count as it did so. I also had to keep an eye on that machine to grab the bags when it had a set of one hundred ready, because otherwise, two sets of bags would end up mixed together and I'd need to count them by hand to separate them back out. When there was time between bag sets, and there always was, I'd go grab the strange tubes, make note of their number, and put them in a box for later. Other than that, all that I needed to do was box the bags and prepare them for shipping. The one part that I didn't like was that I kept strangely becoming unaware of the bag cutter's rhythmic sounds. My mind was blocking it out as background noise, probably. A bit later, I'd be startled by the fact that I couldn't hear it, jump a little and look at the bag machine, then begin hearing it again.

The boss offered me a ride to Pony Village Mall. He said that he was already heading there, and it's would save me a lot of walking to get home, so I accepted. He ended up wanting to take me all the way home though, which was both inconvenient and counterproductive. He wasn't stopping at my home if not giving me a lift, which means that extra fossil fuels were burned. I would have declined his offer if I'd known that he was going to do that. I couldn't exactly refuse to tell him where I live though, which would have prevented it, as then it looks like I'm hiding from him. In addition to the wasted fuel, I actually had business at the Pony Village Mall anyway. I was going to deposit all my money and withdraw one-dollar bills, so to do that, I ended up walking in both directions. I won't complain about that part though, as if he'd not given me a lift at all, the walk would have taken hours to complete. I kind of wonder if he was even really headed to the mall at all though, to be honest. The whole trip might have been for me, which would suck. As he was leaving, he said that he was going "to the mall or something", and if he had already planned to come this way, he'd have known for sure where he was going.

After getting my money changed, I picked up some hash brown patties at the local grocery store. Their potato-based goodness should make it easier to stay energized at work. I had been eating sandwiches at work, but peanut butter and jam that expired over a year ago aren't the most energizing foods.

When I got home, I found that my modem was down. Again. It seems that it was down for two hours before I caught it, yet Tor hadn't failed yet. I wonder what causes Tor to try to restart. It's the restart attempts that trigger the problem, so as long as Tor continues running without restarting, it should be able to stay up without an Internet connection indefinitely.

While building an inventory list of what was and was not on the Professor Shyguy USB drive, I found that Fragmentation now has a bonus track, but only if you order a physical copy. This will be the third time that I've purchased this album ... In any case, I've been wanting to make a new music purchase now that I'm actually employed. More than that, I'm hoping that by sending more money Shyguy's way, he'll be less likely to think that I'm trying to take advantage of him by trying to get as much as I can out of him without paying him what I owe. It's doubtful that he'd think that, but I'm a bit paranoid about these kinds of things. In all honesty, I don't care too much about missing tracks that can be bought separately online, as I'd like to eventually add them to my online collection anyway. However, I fear that USB drive-only tracks may be missing. If that's the case, I'd never know if the tracks were missing. After building the inventory list, I happened to find one of my old USB drives that I could test on, so I formatted it and gave it an ext4 file system. As expected, the drive didn't corrupt its file system or lose files that were put on it. Something is undoubtedly wrong with the Professor Shyguy USB drive, not my machine. Finally, I wrote the following letter to Professor Shyguy:

Greetings Professor Shyguy!

When I received the USB drive that you sent me back in December, I noticed that some of your music wasn't on it. At the time, I wrote it off as not being a big deal. However, on Monday, I tried writing more files to the drive for the first time, which caused the USB drive to exhibit strange behavior and eventually data loss. Putting two and two together, I suspect that the USB drive was damaged in the mail and some of the music files may have been lost before I was able to copy them to my hard drive.

I'm not trying to get you to send another USB drive, but can you please look over this summary of the files I got from it to see if that's all that was supposed to be on the drive? Thank you very much and thank you for all the great music that you write!

On USB drive:
Fragmentation [lossless (WAV)]
Geekotica [lossless (ten are FLAC, one is WAV)]
Rated Heart [lossless (twelve are FLAC, one is WAV)]
Rhythm & Bloops [lossless (WAV)]
History 1-1 [lossless (WAV)]
80s Ep (MAGProm) [lossless (WAV)]
Happy Parallel [MP3 only]
The Instrumentals [twenty-three lossless (FLAC), six missing]
Unplugged: Please Check Connection [lossless (WAV)]
Triforce Tour - Triforce Collected [three MP3 only, seven tracks missing]
Merry Chipmas [lossless (WAV)]
LoL Troll [MP3 only]
Still Alive (Cover) [MP3 only]
Rated Heart [lossless (twelve FLAC, one WAV)]

Not on USB drive:
Happy Parallel [lossless missing, MP3 present]
The Instrumentals [six tracks missing]
Triforce Tour - Triforce Collected [three missing lossless, seven missing entirely]
Diamond Club Movie Draft 2014 [missing]
LoL Troll [lossless missing, MP3 present]
Still Alive (Cover) [lossless missing, MP3 present]
Ruston Family Christmas [missing]

USB drive-only (not available online, unknown completeness):
Pull Paradox (Bonus Track) [MP3 only]
Helix Prophecy [lossless (WAV)]
The White Lie Album [five tracks, MP3 only]
Another One Bytes the Dust (Short) [MP3 only]
Star Stuff (Demo) [MP3 only]

~ Yst Dawson

It's worth noting that some of the albums listed above are nonfree and shouldn't be listened to. I included them in the email only to insure that the summary of files would be complete so that there'd be as little chance of miscommunication as possible. Rather than check the list as I'd asked, he instead offered to potentially send me a me USB drive!:

Is it possible to format the drive or has it gone completely wonky? I've got a new set of drives that have been less temperamental and I can possibly replace that one.

- Brandt

Under normal circumstances, offering to replace the drive would be the correct thing to do. His new drives are "less temperamental", suggesting that he got a bad batch and was shipping a defective batch of USB drives, which he probably didn't find out until later.However, I'd be happy with just the files. If he does end up sending a new USB drive, it'll feel like he's going above and beyond he should do, though I know that that doesn't make any sense. Anyway, I replied about having already tried formatting the drive and what happens when I do that:

I've tried formatting it upwards of twenty times in the past few days (including once today before writing to you). If I format it as ext4 (or anything that isn't FAT32), the file system becomes corrupt upon ejecting the device. If I format it as FAT32, the file system doesn't become corrupt, but files will disappear while still taking up space on the drive (so the drive will look like it contains maybe five files, but the space of ten files is used up). Deleting the visible files shows that the space really is used up, it's not that I don't realize the size of the files. At one point, the drive appeared to be 73% full, but it had zero accessible files.

Ha ha, I'm sorry to be troublesome like this. But I take it that some of the other drives have gotten strange as well? I'm glad to hear that it's not just me.

~ Yst

It's occurred to me that each of my three copies of Fragmentation has come with a different set of extras that's exclusive to that format. The first one was a pre-order, which came with unfinished versions of the songs that could only be downloaded for a limited time. Despite having paid for it, I can't download these again later. The second was the USB drive, which came with a few tracks that were considered to be "odds and ends". Finally, this CD comes with a bonus track that was written for the album, but not considered to be a good enough fit to make a part of the main album. It's a bit strange having three copies of the album on my purchases page though, especially seeing as the downloads offered from there don't contain the bonuses, and are therefore identical. Professor Shyguy says that he'll refund shipping on orders for the CD by people that already ordered a digital version, but I'm not going to try to push for that. I'm already maybe getting a new USB drive from him, which has to cost him something. I'm hoping that he's able to get a refund himself for the screwy USB drive itself, as he didn't make those, he only put them inside a Game Boy game's shell. Still, he's got to pay for the Game Boy games that he dismantles and shipping of the drive, and his time itself to build them is worth something.

Just in time to catch the mail man, I filled out the questionnaire that the jury summons people sent and attached my note to it. I ended up omitting the second paragraph though, the rant about offering a non-telephone way of doing things. I'm trying to get out of jury duty due to the commute to it being too far. I don't need to go needlessly raising any red flags that might make people question the legitimacy of my request. However, that doesn't mean that I'm going to imply that I have telephone service. The form asked for both a daytime telephone number and an evening telephone number, so in both fields, I wrote "no telephone service, use email" and wrote my email address on the bottom. I was going to write it in angle-bracketed URI form, but again, I don't need any mistakes. People might try to use the brackets as part of the email address or think that mailto: is a suspicious thing to have as part of an email address. I'm already using an email domain that many people don't recognize, while at the same time trying to get out of jury duty and not providing a telephone number. I have to at least try to make my response look as legitimate as it actually is. I finished with the questionnaire just in time to meet the mail man as he came by my house for deliveries, so I handed it to him and asked if he'd take it to the post office for me. Of course he would, it's part of his job, but it's polite to ask.

I tried to fix my flat tires next, but that didn't go well. In order to get the old inner tubes off and the new ones on, the wheels needed to be removed as usual. Normally, that's no problem, but one of the nuts on one of the wheels refuses to come off. The usual tool that I use for it has also become corroded by the same wrenched humid air that causes everything here to rot so quickly. This tool, made of an unknown metal, broke off in my bare hands! It had become too weak to withstand the combined strength of the unbudging bolt and my arm. The wrenches that I could find are all the wrong size, with "5/16" being too small and "3/8" being too large. I need an "11/32" or something, and I'm not sure where to get that, or a replacement for the tool that I usually use. It looks like I won't be using the bicycle for a while. I did locate my old lock and chain, but that won't do me any good yet.

I've decided to start taking my laptop to work to type on during my lunch break. I have nothing better to do during this time and it'd save me some time later. I can begin writing my weblog entries from work, then finish later at home.

Tomorrow might be a bit bad. I didn't have time to finish everything that I wanted to get done today, but I got done enough that there isn't time for a full night of sleep. I'd love to get more done, but I'd better not push it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Rubio has dropped out of the presidential race!

Day 00399: Saturday, 2016 April 09

I didn't have time to get a full night's sleep last night, but apparently, my body wasn't going to put up with that. I slept through my alarm and was a few minutes late to work. In the rush, I ended up not bringing my laptop as planned. The boss didn't notice that I was late until I apologized for it though, so there weren't any issues. Additionally, we ended up running out of materials to work with. Though only three people (including both the boss and I) were there today, we all went home an hour and a half early. As we're out of materials to work with, we might not be coming in on Tuesday. The boss said he'd contact us and let us know, depending on if the new shipment came in by then. I tried to ask if I should assume that I should come in if I don't receive word or I should assume not to come in, but he insisted that he'd contact me and let me know either way.

We went back to making the smaller sapling protectors today. It seems that we finished one large order of small sapling protectors, moved on to a small order of larger sapling protectors, and are now on a new order of the smaller size of protectors. The current order was placed by Weyerhaeuser, a company that I recognize as being one of the main lumber companies in my old city, Springfield. A few of the machines were turned off, so the room was a lot quieter than it has been.

I brought a couple hundred one-dollar bills to feed to the snack machine to exchange for coins during the lunch break. I figured that the machine would run out of coins at some point and I'd have to actually choose a snack, but after about twenty bills, the machine just quit accepting paper money, saying that it would only accept coins. I tried the same thing with the soda machine, but it wouldn't fall for that trick. Upon inserting the dollar bill, it spat out one quarter as change without waiting for a selection, then wouldn't allow me to withdraw the remaining money. The only options were to choose an over-priced soda or get nothing. It was worth it just to find out that some machines do this for future reference though. Luckily, I'd put the frozen potato patties in my bag yesterday instead of into the freezer, so even though I had to rush out the door quickly, I did have them with me for lunch. As expected, potato-based food was more energizing than those sandwiches that I've been eating.

With only three of us working, covering the lunch breaks was a challenge. At one point, I was rushing around between the bag machines, the boxing area, and the sapling protector machines. The bag machines had been reconfigured to produce a new type of bag, and now needed to be under constant watch. The first machine spun the bag material out of molten plastic, which was slow because the customer had wanted thick and sturdy bags. Working with that much material slowed the process down. The second machine had to move more quickly though. This second machine was responsible for cutting the bags and sealing the bottoms with heat. If this second machine slowed down, it would burn through the plastic instead of sealing it. In order to keep the cutter/sealer from tugging on the bag material, I needed to shut the cutter/sealer off whenever it started catching up to the extruder and give the extruder time to get ahead again. Once shut off, the cutter/sealer didn't like to start back up either. Most of the time, getting it back in motion only required a hard twist of this rod that stuck out from the side. The part of this rod that was inside the machine was one of the parts pushing the bag material through the machine and presumably was kept in sync with the other rods with gears or something. When I twisted this rod, I was basically forcing the machine out of the position that it was stuck in! At that point, it usually was able to take over and move itself, but other times, I needed to get under the machine and physically move one of the inner wheels that was attached to some sort of band. It made me nervous to do that, though it probably wasn't dangerous as long as you are intelligent enough not to touch the band itself. While keeping an eye on those machines to insure that they didn't play tug of war with the plastic, I also needed to watch the counter on the cutter/sealer so that I could grab sets of twenty-five bags, wrap then in cellophane, and put them in a box. Speaking of boxes, I needed to prepare all the boxes for shipping. Some of these boxes came from me and the bag machines and needed to be shortened because they were too tall. Others came from my boss and the sapling protector machines. These boxes were already the correct size. In either case, the boxes needed to be closed up with what appears to be an air-powered stapler, wrapped in plastic bands, Apply shipping labels, and make note of the box on a paper form. Meanwhile, the boss mostly kept up with the sapling protector machines, which I thought was amazing at the time, but I later found out that he'd set those machines to go slower today after we had finished the large order yesterday. Every once in a while though, he'd fall behind slightly, and there is no catching back up with that machine on your own, even on the slower speed, once you fall behind. Between doing other things, I'd run over and grab the one or two sapling protectors that had slipped by him and take care of them myself. It was a challenge to try to keep up with all of this, but it was kind of fun!

It occurred to me today that this place is a factory. I now work at a factory. I've always wondered what people actually *do* in a factory, as I thought that the machines did everything. In this case, though I don't know about every case, it's been mostly about shipping. The machines generate objects, but they need to be put in sets, wrapped up, and boxed. Additionally, some machines have needed to be watched to make sure that they don't do something stupid and damaging. In the case of the bag machines, they'd have a tug of war match if left to their own devices. In the case of the sapling protector machines, one we noticed at one point that the cutter was damaging the protectors, so having humans there to notice was useful. Mostly though, if we can build machines that can pack stuff, we could reduce human labor in this type of factory.

The boss said that he thought that there'd be more work for me to do next week, but he didn't sound completely sure. Additionally, he was unclear when getting my contact information, so it sounded like my job was over at the time. He said he'd contact me and let me know if I was even needed next week, which sounds like I might not be needed at all, though later conversation revealed that he actually wasn't sure if the shipment of new materials would be in yet, and if it wasn't in, there'd be nothing to have me do. Thinking that this was my last day in the factory, I asked a few more questions than I otherwise would have in one day. Normally, I'd try to ask only a few things at a time in an effort not to bombard people with questions. The main thing that I wanted to know about was how the extruders were generating a mesh material. My admittedly-limited understanding of extrusion was that this didn't happen. Extrusion creates objects that, in one direction, all cross sections are identical. It's like when you shoved toy dough through a hole as a child; you could make really long and funny-shaped noodles that way, but you never ended up with noodles with a mesh pattern. As it turns out though, our extruders do something that I didn't notice in the Wikipedia article (which admittedly, I only had time to skim, not read). Essentially, each of the extruders that I've been working with is two extruders, one inside the other, spinning in opposite directions. Not only can you have a spinning extruder to create a spiral shape, you can nest them to get spirals in opposite directions, forming this mesh! I'm not sure if the output of both extruders is combined while still molten or if it's hardened and melted together later. It looks like the two parts are melted together later, but it seems like it'd make more sense to combine them while still hot. I also asked about our products. The sapling protectors are obviously for protecting saplings. Deer try to eat them, so these plastic cylinders act as a physical barrier so that the deer can't get their mouths around the young trees. The strange tubes have something to do with artificial bee hives. One person said that they are used by bees to put honey in, though this tool used to check the size of the tubes mentions bee-feeding. The flimsy, purple bags from yesterday and the day before are used for putting plant bulbs in, while the thick, black bags made today are placed over plants to keep them from getting too much sun light. Aside from the sapling protectors, none of these are biodegradable, though the so-called "shade cards" are used in the forest and should be.

The boss offered me a ride home again. I should have turned it down, but I was feeling defeated by the fact that I couldn't get my bicycle working, so in a defeat-induced fit of weakened morality, I accepted the ride. I pulled out some cash to offer him gasoline money just to not look like a freeloader, but he declined the offer.

When I set up my URI stamp, I only had upper-case letters and non-letters to work with. At the time, I figured that it was good enough, as DNS is case-insensitive and Web browsers seem to treat the HTTPS: scheme as the same as the https: scheme. Since learning more about URIs though, I haven't gone back to consider my stamp. It occurred to me today that the URI on my stamp is technically correct, though unnormalized. URI normalization lower-cases both the host (aside from any percent-encoded characters, if any) and the scheme, so the URI on my stamp is equivalent to my desired URI. Now that I know that know that https:-scheme URIs are allowed to have trailing dots, I wanted to fix that on my stamp, and I also wanted to add angle brackets around the URI. It turns out that angle bracket characters aren't available in my stamp's character set. After adding the dot though, there are four characters of space left. I can add to the path and reference a particular page that explains the stamp. I'm not yet sure what I want the page's path to be yet though. Also, while looking at my character set, I managed to drop one of the stamp character cases, cracking it. I need to be more careful.

It turns out that Professor Shyguy included a link to a RAR file containing his music in his last letter to me, though I didn't notice it because there was no space between the sentence containing the link and the quoted letter below. I thought that I wouldn't be able to open this RAR file, as most RAR files can't be opened by free software, but this file actually opened. It contained only the MP3 files, so I don't think that Brant understood that part of the problem was the missing lossless files, but it did give me some idea of what was supposed to be there and not. I haven't looked through everything yet, and I'm not sure I will considering later communications with him, but I did see that only three songs from Triforce Tour - Triforce Collected were present and some albums such as Ruston Family Christmas weren't included at all. Brant said that if I mail back the USB drive, he'll send a new one that's less temperamental. I'll compare the files that I already have against the files on this new USB drive when it arrives. I don't have time to ship it out today, and the post office will probably be closed tomorrow, but I'll send it on Monday. I'll be interested to see if he reuses the Game Boy game shell, sending me back the same one with only the USB drive inside replaced. It'd be a waste not to do that. I should be able to tell too, as the one that I have now has a distinguishing chink out of the plastic. They don't make these games any more, so the chances of finding one of these things perfectly intact are pretty slim, even if there was a reason to look for them in mint condition.

My modem seems to be getting worse. I brought the modem back up after it died, only for it to die again right away. I also tested to see if restarting cepo would bring Tor back up, but it doesn't. Tor really doesn't like starting with the correct configuration. The only thing that seems to work is removing the IRC-forwarding hidden service from the Tor configuration, starting Tor, adding the hidden service back in, then sending a HUP signal to Tor.

Cal offered to translate my website for me, as I haven't finished learning Esperanto yet and haven't been able to translate it yet. Two of my websites plan to have such a translation, Yst Domain and this onion. He asked if I have version control for my site's code, but didn't specify which site, so as this onion's code isn't fully available and because I want to translate my weblog entries myself anyway, I made sure to provide a link to Yst Domain's source code. Instead of translating that site though, Cal translated Authored Nansyxlu's source code. That was a bit frustrating. It's not that I mind the help, but Cal's changes can't go live until I've learned Esperanto myself and translated my weblog entries. I feel bad that I can't make use of his addition yet. I don't want him to feel like his efforts aren't appreciated, after all.

I had a bit of time today, so I tried to debug Quod Libet for a bit. Since installing Debian 8 on newdawn, Quod Libet hasn't been able to play music. It appears to be running, but doesn't output any sound for some reason. I tried running Quod Libet from the command line to see if I could get any error messages and I saw this:

yst@newdawn.hn.y.st:~$ quodlibet
0:00:01.016511667 14933      0x17b3210 ERROR             jackclient gstjackaudioclient.c:35:jack_log_error: Cannot connect to server socket err = Dosiero aŭ dosierujo ne ekzistas
0:00:01.016598829 14933      0x17b3210 ERROR             jackclient gstjackaudioclient.c:35:jack_log_error: Cannot connect to server request channel
0:00:01.018728359 14933      0x17b3210 ERROR             jackclient gstjackaudioclient.c:35:jack_log_error: jack server is not running or cannot be started

It looks like the issue might be related to the jack audio client, whatever that is. Taking a wild guess, I tried installing the JACK Audio Connection Kit, which seems to be the server, as the client seemed to already be installed. That didn't work though, and Quod Libet remains silent while continuing to output that error message.

I went out to collect bullet shells again with my mother. On the way home, I noticed the other local-ish temp agency. I might stop by there at some point to do some more job-seeking.

I was going to go out tonight to see if I could get a replacement tool for removing the nuts from the bolts that hold my bicycle wheels on, but it seems that we're headed to Springfield tomorrow. At least every other weekend, perhaps every weekend, I'll be expected to shift my sleep cycle to match that of people that don't have graveyard shifts, while I'll be working graveyard shifts during the week. This is going to be a pain.

It seems that Rubio has dropped out of the presidential race! Most of the remaining candidates still suck, but that's one less bad candidate in the running.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Re-registering to vote

Day 00400: Sunday, 2016 April 10

With Rubio and especially Bush out of the running, I'm becoming less worried about the Republican nominee. Especially considering that I don't know a single Republican nominee that's worth supporting, at this point, I think I'll be more effective voting in the Democratic primaries than the Republican primaries. I've registered to change my party using the online form, which seems to specify that the email address and telephone number fields are optional. It's nice to see that not everyone assumes that everyone else is reachable via these specific methods.

I realized today that I don't have an extra slash character to spare in my stamp's character set, so I can't link to the index of a directory, and with only a four-character space to work in, I can't use the ".xhtml" file extension. I could use a fragment, but that'd require either use of JavaScript or would link to an already-visible part of the main index. I could also choose to use a query string, but that would require me to use dynamic pages instead of static ones. My best option is to just continue linking to the main index. With that in mind, I finished changing my stamp to add the trailing dot on the domain while leaving everything else the same.

We went to Springfield, where I was asked to remove the pair of plant racks from the pillars on the porch. The first time that I was asked to do this, I was only able to remove one of the four bolts. The other three were too stripped to work with. The second time I was asked, I had to remind my mother that I'd already tried that and that the bolts were stripped. This time, she lent me a new socket wrench set that was supposed to have very good grip. The socket wrench can't reach one of the remaining bolts, but it seemed to work partially on one of the others. Before I could make any real progress though, we rushed off to meet one of her friends that she doesn't get to see often.

Her friend likes to smoke, and he smoked at least five cigarettes in the vehicle while we were out. It was a bit obnoxious. I don't want to breathe that poison! We ended up going to the woods where we hiked down to a river. The two of them gathered rocks that they liked while I looked around at plants and tried not to fall into the water. My mother saw a large red frog, though it left before I got a chance to see it. They grabbed more rocks than they could carry though, and decided to leave some in a pile to come back for later. I grabbed the largest of these and hauled it back to the vehicle, though the smaller two were still left behind. Next, we went to another spot where my mother and I gathered bullet shells and her friend dug fired bullets out of the ground. After that, we returned home.

Knowing about the new socket wrench now, I jacked it for a while to try it on my bicycle. That didn't go well. The nut came off the bike, but the socket wrench wouldn't detach from the nut. After much prying, using the axle for leverage, I was able to separate the two, but I fear that I've damaged the axle. I won't know until tomorrow though, when I try to change the inner tubes and reassemble the thing.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Always wear a helmet

Day 00401: Monday, 2016 April 11

With the nuts having been removed yesterday, I replaced my bicycle's inner tubes today. I worried that the bike wouldn't roll so well, as I might have damaged the axle yesterday, and even if I hadn't damaged it, I've never used this second-hand bike before. I may have bought it pre-damaged. I had some errands to run, so I used the bike to both speed the errands and give me a chance to test it out. The bike works, though shifting gears is problematic. The gears on one wheel don't shift at all and the gears on the other can't really be shifted except by moving the chain by hand while the bike is stopped. If you try to use the gear-shifting mechanism on the bike's handle bars, the chain comes off so that peddling no longer has an effect. I don't currently have the strength to ride up all these stupid hills either. I'll need to work on building up my leg muscles. I had also forgotten how much of a pain my bike lock is to use. It unlocks easily, but it doesn't like to lock. I have to jam the locking curved bar into the hole dozens of times before the locking mechanism will function. Sometimes, the locking mechanism simply won't catch, but most of the time, the locking mechanism won't even allow the bar to fit into place. I've put up with this issue since first removing the lock from it's factory packaging. I'm done with this. I don't have the energy to deal with it any more. On the way home from work tomorrow, I'll stop by this store that I pass and see if they sell key-based locks. Most combination locks aren't a problem, but if this lock were a key lock, it wouldn't be acting up.

My first stop was at the post office. I told Brant Cooley that I'd mail back the USB flash drive today. I sent it back as first-class mail because that's how he'd sent it when he had sent it to me, at which point the post office representative gave me a tracking number. I explained that the USPS website is broken and doesn't allow me to track packages. I pulled up the site on my mobile to show her the 403 error. She thought that strange, and when I asked if there was someone that I could contact about the issue, she said that I should do a Web search for the information and come back if I couldn't find it. I'll probably do that later, but not today.

I stopped at a store for hash brown patties for lunch at work tomorrow, and I found that I'd only stamped one side of some of my dollar bills. I need to be more careful about that. I also found vegan jelly beans. I haven't been able to eat jelly beans in over a year, so that was a nice surprise.

On the way home, I approached a spot where the sidewalk ended while traveling downhill. I didn't brake as early as I should have, so I made the transition at too quick of a speed. The bike got caught and I was thrown off of it. I broke my helmet in the process as well as ripped my shorts. This is my first time riding in this area and it's not the most bike-friendly terrain, so I'm going to need to work on learning all the quirks of the land and how to deal with them. Thankfully, my mother later lent me her helmet, which she hardly ever uses herself. If I broke a helmet falling of the bike, riding home without a working helmet sounds like a really bad idea.

I tried installing the libjack0 package to fix Quod Libet, but that didn't really work. Quod Libet no longer outputs an error message, but it still doesn't output any sound either.

The boss still hasn't contacted me. He insisted that I wouldn't have to make an assumption about whether to come to work if he didn't contact me, as he'd be sure to contact me either way. However, it seems that this was a lie. This is very frustrating. I suppose I'll come in then, and if I don't work, I don't work.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A pointless trip to work

Day 00402: Tuesday, 2016 April 12

The boss said that he'd contact me to let me know if he wanted me to come into work or not. I asked whether I should come in or not if I didn't contact me, but he wouldn't give me an answer. Instead, he insisted that he would contact me either way. However, he never contacted me. I went into work to ask about it, and he was surprised that no one had contacted me. Apparently, he wasn't doing the contacting himself, he had delegated. He gave me new instructions, this time with an action for when no one contacts me: don't come in *until* someone contacts me. Next time something like this happens, I'm going to insist that a default action be established, saying that I've had problems with people not contacting me in the past.

Someone from work later contacted me, so it seems I do need to go into work tomorrow.

I was going to pull my bicycle out of the van, but my mother thought that it'd be a good idea for me to leave it in unless I was sure I'd need it today. In what way is that a good idea? It's not difficult to load or unload it, but now I'm stuck without it for the day.

I finished documenting the function-loading class so that it could be committed and I could begin work on a new function for dealing with Tor's crashing issue. Once the new function was complete, I was able to verify that it did work around Tor's issues. The problem is that Tor is choking on DNS names for some reason. With the DNS names removed from the configuration file, Tor no longer complains. I'm still not sure what's causing the underlying issue, but at least Tor will be able to stay up when my modem fails. I'm not going to document or commit this new function just yet. I'm too tired at the moment.

Considering picking up a new album, I paid a visit to Bandcamp, where I noticed that Fragmentation's cover art has changed. In addition to taking on a lighter hue, it also now has a "FULL ALBUM" strip plastered across it. Looking into it, Rated Heart has the same banner, Geekotica now has one that reads "FREE ALBUM", and one was added to History 1-1 and a proprietary album that says "COVER ALBUM". Now I wish I'd gotten History 1-1 before it had been changed; it looks better without the banner. On History 1-1, it doesn't actually pose as much of an issue as on the other albums, but it obscures Professor Shyguy's name on one album as the album name on the other three. Additionally, Professor Shyguy's artist name has been removed from Rated Heart's album cover for some reason. I almost ended up deciding not to buy any music today though. I currently have four musical items waiting only to be delivered by postal mail. Two are from Josh Woodward's Kickstarter campaign: Addressed to the Stars and a prerelease copy of an unknown album. Two are from Professor Shyguy: a new USB drive and a special edition copy of Fragmentation with a bonus track. Until at least some of that has arrived, I was thinking that I probably shouldn't get greedy and buy anything else. However, I'm celebrating finally having a job, at least for a bit, and I'm not actually wanting these physical items, just the music that they come with, some of which I already have. I ended up buying Aligned Archetype, taking the oportunaty to include another note to Kellee Maize about how I'd love it if she used the CC BY or CC BY-SA license for her other two albums on Bandcamp, the two that I haven't bought. On her own website, she claims that all her work is under the CC BY license, so she's not against the use of that license for her albums.

I'm going to bring a resume to work tonight so that I can have it if I need it when I walk into the other temp agency on my way home from work tomorrow. The temp agency's a bit far away, but as I have to pass by it anyway, I might as well make a stop there.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Multi-album sets on Bandcamp

Day 00403: Wednesday, 2016 April 13

My mother says that she doesn't know how much longer that she can give me rides to work. Apparently, staying up late gives her headaches. I'm not happy that she has been having headaches, but hopefully this means that she's going to stop being wiggy and about me going to work on my own. I'm beyond legal drinking age, I think that I can get myself to work just fine. I was already planning to time my ride home, but my mother said that it'd be a good idea to do so today. Is this a sign that she's not giving me a ride tonight? It turned out that it was. Not having to take rides from her will relieve a lot of stress. For one thing, it bothers me that my commute was burning fossil fuels. In addition to that though, I could never be sure that we'd leave on time or that she'd remember to take me at all. She hadn't caused any issues in commuting to work, but in the past, she'd almost always bring Vivian and me to our school orchestra performances late. She'd insist that we didn't need to be there as early as the orchestra teacher had said that we needed to arrive for preparations, as she didn't understand that preparation work needed to be completed; we couldn't just show up just before the audience.

When my mother saw the seat of my bike, she got a bit weird. Apparently, she didn't know how damaged the seat was, despite it being that damaged when we bought it. She must have forgotten, as I haven't used this bike since we got it, at least not until recently. It hasn't gotten any more damaged. Furthermore, she's the one that pointed out this bike and said that we should get it. It shouldn't be too damaged for use in her opinion. In any case, she wants me to keep a plastic shopping bag over the seat, as if that doesn't look even more trashy. She also insisted that I ask where to put the bike. There were several obvious places to put it outside and out of the way, but I humored her and asked the boss if there was any specific place that he preferred that I put it or if I should just put it anywhere out of the way. He actually had a place inside the building for it, which was both unexpected and inconvenient. It was off behind several boxes, so getting it in and out was a pain, but I suppose that it at least kept the bike out of the rain.

I decided not to bring my laptop today. I wanted to use it during my lunch break, but I was afraid that it would be a pain to ride home with it. Once we arrived, it started raining though, which reminded me of the unpredictable weather. The rain had cleared up by the time I rode home, but there's no telling when it's going to rain here. I shouldn't bring my laptop to work, as it could easily become damaged by the rain.

I managed to forget my resume at home, so I didn't go into the temp agency. I'll try to bring it tonight so that I can walk into the temp agency tomorrow morning.

The machines at work were moving a lot slower today. At first, I thought it too slow, but it was later helpful. The stools had gone missing and I didn't get enough sleep because of the lack of information about a shift yesterday, so by the end of the shift, I was thankful that the machines weren't going any faster. I also didn't have any potato products to eat at lunch, further increasing my energy deficit.

It took me an hour and a quarter to ride home, and I made a couple stops in an effort to get a more realistic estimate. I might very well stop on any particular trip if I pass somewhere that would be useful to drop in on. Additionally, the timing doesn't account for the fact that the hill slopes will be reversed when traveling in the opposite direction. I figure that at least at first, I should give myself an hour and a half to get to work, giving me a further extra quarter hour to account for the unexpected. This bike is a pain though. The gear on the wheel resets itself if you try to change it by hand and there's no lever for changing it correctly. The gear on the pedals has only two gears, with an empty spot for a third one present. This gear can't be changed using the lever, as turning the lever one direction seems to have no effect and changing it the other direction causes the chain to drop into the spot that looks like a third gear should exist in. It certainly sped up my journey, but this bike really isn't the best bike I've ever used.

I found something unusual on Bandcamp today. One can buy Chris Zabriskie's albums as one item. I've never seen that sort of thing at Bandcamp. I needed to make that purchase in order to understand better how it works. Do all the albums end up added to your Bandcamp music collection page? It seems that they do, though it causes Bandcamp to forget how much you paid, which they normally keep track of forever. It would be nice if Professor Shyguy's USB drive came with such a set instead of with a single album, as supposedly, all of that music comes on the USB drive. For example, I can't leave a review for Happy Parallel because while I did buy it from the artist, I don't have it in my BandCamp collection. I paid a bit more than I wanted to for Chris Zabriskie's work, considering that I'm not really a fan of ambient music, and that's what he produces. However, it was a useful experiment, providing information for future reference, and I didn't want to appear insulting by paying him too little. Additionally, he never did give me a way to buy the albums of his old, defunct band, Low-Fi is Sci-Fi, so in a way, this payment can kind of be for those albums.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A bicycle crash and a jury summons deferment

Day 00404: Thursday, 2016 April 14

I wanted to pick up some fast food for lunch on the way to work, but it seemed that everywhere was closed. On the way home though, I stopped at the one fast food restaurant that I hadn't stopped at before, due to it being on the next street over. Subway is open until midnight! I guess I'll be stopping there tonight to pick up a sandwich for lunch tomorrow.

I made it most of the way to work last night, but then I hit a bad spot in the sidewalk. It was too dark to see and the path was crumbling away on one side. In the dark, I couldn't risk riding too closely to the street, as I'd ride off the curb and attempt to ride back onto it, which would result in my falling over. I didn't have bike lights yet. I was technically riding illegally, but I didn't have much choice; I hadn't had time to go shopping for bike lights yet, and before this job, I wasn't one to ride at night. It seems I rode too far from the street though. I didn't know that I was that close to the other edge or that the other edge was falling apart. I scraped my elbow and took a decent chunk out of the skin on my opposite thumb. Luckily, it was my right thumb that took damage, as I prefer to work left-handedly. I didn't have time to stop riding though, so I got back on and rode the rest of the way to work. I had been playing music on the way to work, which alerted me to the fact that my mobile had fallen out of my pocket as well. As I rode on, the music stayed behind me! If not for the fact that I was playing music, I would have lost the mobile entirely. I nearly fell into another collapsed section of the sidewalk, but I managed to see it in time and steer around it. By this time, I had turned off the music and had started holding the mobile in my hand, using its torch to faintly light the way. This is another reason that I shouldn't bring my laptop to work. If I'm going to go falling off my bike, I risk damaging my laptop, which I can't afford to replace.

Once I got to work, I was able to assess the damage a bit better. My backpack was scraped up. My container of marinara that I brought to pour on pasta for lunch had broken and my red B vitamin drink mix had popped open. The mixed red mess was everywhere, but very little of it was actually blood. My hands were stained red and I had quite a mess to clean up. I ended up having to clock in late.

Of four people, only two of us, the boss and I, even showed up for our shift. The boss called in the boss from another shift, so there were three of us, but we were still very rushed. We had two sapling protector extruders/cutters set up today, and the two bosses worked on one, while I worked on the other. I'm the temporary worker that doesn't have as much experience with this, but I'm the one that didn't get any help, while the bosses, who should have the most experience, got to work together and thus work at a slower pace. This job is hard work and the commute is a pain. I'm really earning what little sleep I get.

I came off my first break early, feeling a bit guilty that I clocked in late. I use my mobile as a timer to time breaks so I don't stay too long, so when I went back to work early, it went off a bit later. With work being so fast-paced, I didn't think that I'd be able to turn off the timer, but it actually turned itself off after a while. That's good knowledge to have for later; I don't need to make sure that I have time to turn off the timer.

The boss that usually doesn't work through most of my shift offered me more work for next week. I was likely going to otherwise be laid off due to lack of work to complete, but as long as I can switch shifts, I will have work for next week!

I'm not sure if it was because my regular boss took pity on me or because he thought that I needed a break, but he had me just assemble boxes during the final half of my shift. Either way though, I appreciated it a lot! The shifts overlap by half an hour, so the next shift's workers had arrived and were able to cover my position at the extruder. Assembling boxes is busy work, but it's not as rushed as trying to keep up with a machine. Instead, the only machine is just a large fancy stapler, and it waits for you. Getting to walk between the stacks of flat boxes to grab short stacks and the stapler to bind the boxes was also a nice chance to stretch my legs.

I went into the store on the way home to buy potato patties for the next couple days and a more usable bike lock. I forgot to grab the lock though. Whatever. If I can wait until the end of next week before getting a new lock, I'll be able to get a new lock from my old house. The rain ruined my resume though, so I wasn't able to hand that in at the other temp agency. Additionally, they gave me an application to fill out, so I brought that home after the rain had stopped. I'll fill it out as time allows.

I received a follow-up postcard about the jury summons. They have deferred my jury summons to next April. The person said that if transportation is still an issue at that time, I am to telephone her. I guess that she didn't take into account the fact that I mentioned not having telephone service; I can't call her. I might not even be in the county next April, so it might not be a problem, but if I'm still here, I'm going to have a long commute ahead of me.

I found that my mobile was no longer capable of using MTP, which severely limits its usefulness to me! However, after a bit of experimenting, it seems that it's actually just no longer capable of using MTP over its usual cord, though that cord is still able to charge the device. The device is able to use a different cord for MTP, a cord that I hadn't used before today. I think that my other cord got damaged when I crashed my bicycle. I'll add that to the total damage done.

I didn't have time to get to sleep on time tonight. There's just so much to get done and so little time to do it in.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Getting lost, getting laid off, and fixing up my bicycle

Day 00405: Friday, 2016 April 15

When my mother heard about my accident last night, she ran out and bought me bicycle lights. I was going to do that as time allowed, but she didn't want to wait any longer. I left for work even earlier last night than the night before, though I didn't quite get away from the house as quickly as I'd hoped to. Trying to get to work as quickly as possible, I let gravity do all the work on any downhill slopes, not breaking any more than I had to. I cried literal tears out of fear of the speed. I took a new route to work trying to minimize my uphill stretches, but the streets didn't connect up the way that I thought that they did and I ended up lost. As the streets in this section of town were straight, I just kept following the road that I was on, figuring that it'd lead me in the correct direction. That is, until I crossed the boundary between North Bend and Coos Bay, the name of the street that I was on changed, and I recognized the new street name, Koosbay (sic) Boulevard, as being that of a street that lies perpendicular to the direction that I thought that I was going. Koosbay Boulevard intersects with a street that I know that I can use to get to work though, so I continued following it, trying to figure out how I'd gotten turned around so badly. As it turned out, I didn't get turned around at all; Koosbay Boulevard curves. There was an opportunity to keep going straight as Koosbay Boulevard peeled away, but I was done with being lost. I was getting frustrated with how difficult the bicycle was to peddle in the gear that it's stuck in, and didn't need to add having no idea where I am to that frustration.

Once back in familiar territory, I rode past a couple establishments with homeless people curled up under blankets in front of their doors. It must suck being homeless. They looked cold. My life sucks. My home situation isn't great, I hate my long commute, and I hate graveyard shift. But unlike them, at least I have a house to sleep in; a relative fortress against weather, dogs, and wild city animals.

I stopped in at Subway for a sandwich to take to work to supplement the potato patties that I had. I asked for my usual sandwich, the one without meat, and they didn't even ask what cheese I wanted. They just didn't give me any. That's awesome! At other Subways, I always need to decline the cheese. This subway must not offer cheese on their vegetable sandwiches. I think that the sandwich, combined with the potato patties, made all the difference for me today. I didn't get enough sleep, but I also didn't feel overly exhausted. I held up fairly well.

I didn't get as much time to rest between my commute and when I had to clock in as I'd hoped for. I figured at the time that it was because of the strange path that I'd taken to get to work.

I made it today's goal to listen to four music albums from my Bandcamp collection so that I could select the tracks to choose as my favorites on my Bandcamp account. The bosses here are much more of sticklers to the law than the bosses at my former place of employment, and legally, they must give me at least two breaks and one meal period, all three of which would give me a chance to switch albums. The boss ended up giving me an extra five-minute break at one point though, so I managed to get through five albums! I must admit, the ambient music is somewhat torturous. I can stand it if it's just playing around me, but to have it playing in my headphones and trying to decide which track is my favorite is a bit much.

Today, we only had three workers including the boss and myself again, though this time, the third worker wasn't the other boss. I ended up working on the other sapling protector machine, the one that the two bosses worked with yesterday, along with the other regular worker. No wonder the two bosses worked this machine together yesterday! It was set up to produce larger protectors, and these protectors are a real pain in the neck to deal with. Having just as thin of walls as the regular sapling protectors but also having a wider channel down the middle, these things lack the structural integrity that the smaller ones have. It's far too easy to make them cave in when grouping them.Once they've caved in, there's often no fixing them, and you end up having to start over. On top of that, they are wider than the tube on the cutter that they come out of, so they come out of the machine pre-collapsed. They must be straightened up, put together, and kept from caving while together. The extra care that needs to be put into these ones greatly slows down the process. There's no way to rush this, and having any less than two people working this machine is unacceptable. I got too close to the conveyor belt at one point though, and I ended up with black grease all over my light tan shirt. Hopefully, that will come out in the wash.

One of the bag extruders was set up, but without the sealer/cutter. Instead, it was paired with a mechanized spool that wound up all the extruded bag material. I asked about what it was, and it seems that it's oyster netting. I didn't realize that you could catch oysters in a net, I thought that they attached themselves to the sea floor. This being a strange and very different product than what we've been making, asked about our limitations. Can we produce whatever the customer asks for as long as it has that same mesh-like texture? The boss responded that we're limited in size and that the extruders that we use always extrude in a diamond-weave pattern (which is what I'd meant by having the mesh-like texture), but other than that, we can in fact extrude arbitrary goods that our customers ask for.

One of my coworkers from the next shift caught me after my shift eating potato patties and warned me that potato consumption can lead to diabetes. His logic was that potatoes turn into starch and starch turns into sugar. Potatoes are already made of mostly starch though, they don't "turn into" it. He also said that there is a reason that most diabetics avoid potatoes. I explained that I needed the potatoes for energy, otherwise, I am always tired, then asked what alternatives he recommended. He recommends fruit, peanuts, and green tea. I forget what the green tea is for, but the protein in peanuts can be broken down for energy and the fruit contains sugars. But if sugars are the enemy, how is fruit a decent choice? Once I got home, I did some research on potatoes and diabetes. I couldn't find any information that said that potato consumption can or cannot lead to diabetes, but I did find information that well-informed diabetics don't avoid potatoes. Additionally, a type of sweet potato is actually believed to be good for diabetics. As I can't find any information that actually says that potatoes are a risk factor, I'm not giving them up for now. Fruit's sugar is good for energy spikes, but not sustained energy and heavy peanut consumption to replace potatoes would make me fatter than I already am. Being further overweight is probably a bigger risk factor for diabetes than the potatoes are.

On the way home, I ran into my boss. It seems that he's spoken with the boss that offered me the alternative shifts, and they feel that there isn't enough work to be done to justify keeping me around. I'll speak with the other boss about it myself tomorrow, but it looks like tomorrow is likely my last day there.

I quickly found that my tire was flat on the way home. What in the world? I'd just replaced that inner tube! I debated about making a detour and stopping at a store that sells inner tubes on my way home. I didn't want to go the extra distance, I was already tired and had to walk most of the way home, dragging the bike with me. In the end though, I decided that it was best to make the extra stop. If I actually needed the replacement inner tube, I'd be saving myself another trip. More importantly, I'd be sure that my mother wouldn't interfere and make the trip via a fossil-fuel-guzzling motorized vehicle. If it turned out that I didn't actually need the inner tube, at least I'd have a spare for next time I needed one.

While I was at the store, I found a bike lock that uses letters to form a password instead of numbers! I figured that I'd set the password to something only people that actually know me would ever think of and it'd be easy to remember. After getting it though, I found much to my disappointment that the password isn't settable. I'm stuck with the default password, "MIME". I wouldn't have bought the lock if I'd known that; I should have read the package more closely. I suppose "MIME" is fine as long as I pretend that it is referring to "Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions" and not people that pain their faces and avoid speaking.

I took a shortcut through the woods to get home from the store, but I ended up getting lost again. I came out of the woods at the wrong spot, but it was still closer to home than I would have been in that time if I'd taken the street route.

Once home, I found that my inner tube's valve stem had been broken off and the inner tube had been stretched far beyond the size that it should have been. Did this happen in the crash? If so, it'd explain my difficulty is riding *to* work today. I assumed that I was just stuck on a bad gear, as the bike is stuck on one gear, unable to shift. I guess I'll find out tonight.

I might have gotten enough sleep today if I hadn't been dealing with the bum tire, but that took a large chunk of time. The tire wouldn't even come off until I'd wrestled the inner tube out of it. Maybe tomorrow I can get more sleep.

My first paycheck came in the mail, but it was from the temp agency, not my workplace. Are they paying me through the temp agency? I did see that listed as one of the services that the temp agency provides.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A week in Springfield ...

Day 00406: Saturday, 2016 April 16

As I rode to work last night, I quickly came across a police officer that appeared to be lying in wait in the dark, presumably trying to catch people committing traffic violations. It's a good thing that my mother bought me these bicycle lights after all! I still haven't had time to look into how to shop for good bicycle lights, so I wouldn't have gotten them myself yet. I can handle the injuries, but I don't need the law coming down on me too. Then again, while I do have time to get myself injured, I don't have time or money to continually replace inner tubes either. Later on in my ride, I came across another police officer that might have hassled me about not having lights, but this one didn't appear to be be looking for trouble. Instead, he'd just stopped at a fast food joint for a bite to eat.

I stopped at Subway again for another sandwich, running into the same employee that didn't ask about cheese last time. This time however, he did. Maybe it's not policy after all that this Subway doesn't add cheese to vegetable sandwiches. That's too bad.

I'm now almost certain that I already had my flat tire before I began riding to work two days ago. Lack of gear shifting or not, peddling was much easier. I'm convinced that the inner tube only became damaged because I crashed the bicycle. As long as I use these lights and behave reasonably carefully, there shouldn't be a repeat of this any time soon.

Yesterday, three out of the five albums that I listened to were ambient music. Ambient music really isn't suitable for listening to while trying to perform very fast labor, and it was not a pleasant experience. Today, I was not going to do that again! Instead of attempting to start my reviews on new albums, I just shuffled together all of my Professor Shyguy music and Brant Cooley music, minus the album The Instrumentals. I wasn't going to torture myself with music that was unfit for working today; working here is hard enough as it is.

It turned out to be an easy last day of work, though I found out that the boss doesn't get a lunch break. Is that even legal? How do I sign up to work and get paid during those thirty minutes? I'm not sure if the ease of work had to do with the machines being slowed down or if I was just better prepared. I had a nice sandwich for a proper meal, I had potatoes for sustained energy, and I had upbeat Shyguy music playing in one ear. Near the end of my shift, the boss said something about us being watched, and showed me the camera that had been recording me over the past couple weeks. In a semi-public setting like this, I assumed that I'd been watched at all times, but I just didn't know from what angle until now. It occurred to me too that maybe I'm not an employee of this factory's company, but of the temp agency. My paycheck did come from the temp agency, after all. I asked my boss about that, and he confirmed my suspicion. So what is my job title then? What do I put on my resume? The paperwork says that the position that I'm filling is that of an extruder (I guess the position has the same name as the machine), but that's not my position with the temp agency. Do I even have a title to put on a resume? Should I just call myself a temporary worker? When I get a chance, I should ask the temp agency about that. I didn't have time for that today though. The boss also said some things about how he received his pay through the temp agency too, which a bit latter, made me wonder if he too is a temporary worker somehow. I get the impression that he's been there for quite a while though. Before the shift was scheduled to end, we filled the order that we were working on, which was the last in our queue. The other employee took off. I'm not sure if he was told to or not, but I didn't hear the boss tell me to go, so I stayed. I kind of hung out near the boss so that he'd know I was there, but stayed out of his way while he reconfigured the extruder for Monday's work crew. He gave me occasional instructions, but there wasn't much that he could have me do. He ended up showing me the extruder in a bit more depth, presumably because I'd showed interest before, so I took the opportunity to ask a few other question I had about it. As I had suspected, the water is used purely for cooling. It isn't needed for anything else. Having so little time lately though, I didn't get to writing this weblog entry as soon as I should have, so I can't recall what else I've learned. I should have taken better notes, if nothing else.

The other boss didn't show up today. I was going to confirm with him that he was canceling the shift that he'd offered me. Instead, I just double-checked with the boss on duty that I was not to show up next week and wouldn't be in trouble if I didn't show. Of course, getting in trouble was actually the least of my worries. I just needed an excuse to ask again and be sure, as I would really love to keep my job if possible. It's not the best job, but it provides a paycheck and doesn't require me to produce proprietary software/media.

On the way home, I found that my bicycle's seat was coming apart at the front, exposing some strange, small, metal spikes. These spikes were damaging my pants. I stopped at the store to pick up some duct tape to repair it. The bike seat already looks like trash, a little duct tape won't make it any worse. The bicycle seat covers at that place are way too expensive though, and would have cost more than the second-hand bicycle did. As I was about to check out, I noticed the health food section. Instead of being in the food half of the store, it was in the non-food half. No wonder I didn't find it before! They don't seem to carry vegan fake cheeses though, which is a let down.

It seems that my mother wants me to work on cleaning up our old house and boxing stuff for about a week. I will very likely not have Internet access, so I might not be able to update the weblog in that time. Also, if the modem goes down, I won't be there to bring it back up. Thankfully, I have the workaround in place for that Tor bug that was causing Tor to shut down when the modem goes down. When my siblings or mother get around to resetting the modem, Tor will be ready to continue taking connections and providing this onion and its services. It seems that my mother and I leave for Springfield tomorrow.

I didn't get much rest, as almost as soon as I got home, we all (Cyrus, Vanessa, our mother, and I) headed out to places unknown to me at the time. On the way, my mother was going on about how she thinks that war veterans should be identifiable even without their veteran paperwork and that they should have some sort of marking on their DMV ID cards. I explained that there is an optional designation that they can get on their ID cards, so she said that this designation should be mandatory. What? Has she no sense of privacy whatsoever? What if they don't want to self-identify? Based solely on the privacy issues, this would be completely unacceptable. Cyrus tried to explain that to our mother, but she just went off about how they should be proud and whatnot, so they should want this to be mandatory. The thing is though, if they want it, it wouldn't need to be mandatory; they'd just get the designation that she wants them all to have. To force it on them is to treat them as lesser, not greater, for having, as she puts it, "served our country". If these people truly are as great as she feels that they are, we shouldn't be forcing anything on them above and beyond what we force on our civilians. On a more technical note though, we'd have to overhaul the system somehow to provide the forced designation that my mother wants. The thing is, they provide the designation when you ask for it, but you have to bring in proof of veteran status at that time. To make it mandatory, you'd need nonveterans to prove that they aren't veterans, otherwise, a veteran could simply neglect to bring in their proof. Honestly, should there be proof of nonveteran status? How would one even obtain proof that they are indeed not a veteran? That seems outright idiotic and serves only so that people can pry into business that isn't their own. We already live in a surveillance state, we don't need to make it worse, especially for arbitrary and freedom-restricting reasons.

On the way out, I asked our mother to stop at the bank. If I'm headed to Springfield tomorrow, I'll need food money, and by the time she said we'd be back, the bank would be closed. However, the bank's lobby was closed and they were only providing drive-through service. Pedestrians could walk through, but there was a long line and I didn't want to hold my mother up from what she wanted to go do. I'll just make due with what money I have. Later, I regretted that decision though. It turned out that the place that she hadn't told me that we were going was some sort of emergency preparedness training with the people that she's upset that I don't want to prove my identity to! When we got there though, it seemed that she was wrong or had mistakingly called it a "training", as it was really just a bunch of random booths set up, one of which was run by the emergency preparedness group and the rest of which were not. They had a drawing, which asked for a name and telephone number, so I asked if I could use an email address instead. They said that that was fine, though I'm not going to win, so it didn't really matter.

After visiting the booths, we all headed for the hills to pick up bullet shells again. I was exhausted by this point, though I started to get out of the vehicle. It seems that my mother has assumed that I'd stay in and try to get some rest though, so I sat back down and tried to do that. I didn't really get any until they had finished and we were nearly home. I fell asleep for what I assume was only several minutes, as I remember seeing landmarks near home and Cyrus says that I wasn't out in the vehicle alone for very long.

My Josh Woodward album, Addresses to the Stars, came in the mail today, along with a piece of paper that he'd written on during the song-writing process. Some people probably paid more towards Woodward's Kickstarter campaign to get one of these, but I only paid more to get my name in the album cover. There's an off chance that someone will try to figure out who these people are, which would lead people to my website. The more that I think about it though, maybe it wasn't the brightest idea; the chance of this leading to any visitors is slim. Now that I have the paper note from Woodward though, I might as well take a closer look at it. I'm too tired to make sense of it right now, but when I get back from Springfield, I'll see what's on it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cover blown

Day 00407: Sunday, 2016 April 17

Today's Esperanto lesson involved translating times of day. If my understanding is correct, Esperanto doesn't have a concept of "a.m." or "p.m.". Instead, it might be required that one use a twenty-four hour clock. That's awesome! Twelve-hour clocks are foolish in this day and age. My understanding is that they are an artifact from back when people used the position of the sun and the other stars to tell the time of day. One cycle/system was needed for day, the other for night. Once more sophisticated time pieces were developed, such as clocks, there was no longer any need to break the day into two parts.

Before we left, Cyrus offered me our father's Wi-Fi password. I was reluctant to take it at first, as I'd be using our father's Wi-Fi connection without his knowledge, but I did end up accepting it. I won't be without an Internet connection after all.

Mostly, my mother and I just ran various errands around Springfield all day and didn't work on the house. For the most part, that involed visiting garage sales and second hand stores. We didn't even reach all the second hand store that she wanted to reach though because she got tired. Her job is to wrangle little monsters all day, so it makes sense that she'd lack energy. I also don't see her eating many potato products to boost her energy level.

At one sale, the person running it gave us a gratis back brace just because he didn't want to have to keep it. In the coming weeks, I'll probably try to use that to relieve some of the pain in my own back, as my mother wasn't interested in that one and has at least two already. We were out for quite a while though, and my mother was able to stop at a restaurant to feed herself, but she of course chose a place that wasn't vegan-friendly. I wasn't able to eat there obviously, so I was getting pretty hungry after a while. While she stopped in at a second hand store near my former workplace, I stopped in at my former workplace to order some breadsticks sans cheese. The person working the till was one of my former coworkers, and we talked for a bit, but he never rang my order into the register. When he later came back with my order, I reminded him that he hadn't taken my money yet, so he said "Yst, I'm not going to take your money.". Sweet! Gratis breadsticks.

My mother has clarified her instructions to me, and I am not to box everything as was originally thought to be the plan. Instead, she wants me to box only what we are keeping, as well as clean and vacuum the place. None of the remaining stuff is mine, it's mostly hers. I don't mean that in a "she has more junk than me" sort of way, as a lot of it if family-used stuff, but how am I possibly to know what she wants kept and not? The instructions have become impossible to follow, and I'm just going to have to do the best that I can.

My father wasn't around when my mother dropped me off, so she wanted me to try to keep a low profile and remain unnoticed by him for as long as possible. I wasn't able to bring canned foods or make use of the canned food here at the old house though, as I couldn't seem to find my can opener before we left for Springfield. Because of that, I had to head to the local grocery store tonight to get something to eat. He spotted me. It's been less than a day, and as luck would have it, he rode by on his motorcycle the first time I set foot outside the house. Lovely. I told him that I wouldn't be here long, which isn't actually a lie, so hopefully he'll take that to mean that I was to leave later tonight and that I'm already gone by now.

Before she took off, my mother bought all but seven of my single-dollar bills from me. The banks won't be open until tomorrow, so I left the twenty-dollar bills from her at the house. I ended up getting just over seven dollars worth of supplies at the store though, so when the cashier rang me up, I asked her to take off one of the items, as I didn't have the money at the moment. She asked if it was just the change that I didn't have, then just *gave* me the extra eighteen cents! Eighteen cents isn't much, but still, she didn't have to do that, and it really made my day.

Once we were in Springfield, I remembered that I'd forgotten to bring a pillow and blanket like I'd been planning to. I knew that there was a single mattress here, but nothing else really for sleeping. I moved the mattress to a usable spot on the floor, then managed to find a very flat pillow and a tiny broken electric blanket. The blanket doesn't heat anymore and doesn't cover me, while the pillow is far too flat to provide support, but that's what I get for being absentminded and forgetting to bring my own. I'm lucky that these are even here! With my father around, I couldn't turn on a noisy vacuum cleaner, as I'd get caught again, so I just tried to settle in for the night.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

CD technology is a pain.

Day 00408: Monday, 2016 April 18

Predictably, the modem went down today. When it came back up, I asked Cyrus if he'd reset it, but he said that Vanessa had done it. It was down for several hours while they were in school, but Tor is still running on cepo, so the bug workaround must be working.

The nearby bank wouldn't change my money for smaller bills, which is strange, as they've done it before. It seems that they've changed their system, and an account number is needed even for something as simple as making change, even though no changes are made to the account whatsoever. I thought that I wouldn't have much to eat today, but then I ended up taking a trip to my old work place to try to get used boxes that they always throw out. They didn't have any boxes, but because I was in the area, I stopped by one of my credit unions. They didn't even require me to have an account to make change, though I made sure to bring my ID in case they did require an account. Later in the day, I also found my can opener in my bag where I thought that I'd put it, but I wasn't able to find it before we left. I have both cash and a stock of random cans that can eat from.

I'm at a loss as to what to do. I'm supposed to vacuum this place while avoiding boxing things that we're not keeping, but I can't honestly make any progress with all this stuff scattered about. I have no idea what we're keeping and not, but the fact is, the floors are covered in junk. If I don't box it and get it out of the way, I can't actually get much vacuuming done. I stopped by my former place of employment to ask them for boxes, but they'd already thrown them out for the night. Overwhelmed, I mostly took the day off to collect my thoughts and plan for the job ahead of me. I did box up the piles of magazines in the living room though. I'll check back tomorrow to see if I can get more boxes.

A long time ago, I saw someone mention ripping vinyl records into MP3 files on television. Assuming that this wasn't a plot hole and they weren't using some made-up technology, could I not do the same, but rip into FLAC files instead? I decided to look into what it would take to rip the bonus record that I got from Marc when I ordered Unicorns Get More Bacon. Attempting to look up the name of this record, it seems that I neglected to mention it by name, but the thought of being able to make use of the record after all intrigued me. This was just a passing whimsical thought, but it was worth looking into if for no other reason than to help me relax. I read an article on ripping vinyl records into digital files, and it seems too expensive to me. A cheap USB turntable would cost about $100 USD. More interestingly though, the article mentions that when you rip a CD, track information is added automatically. If this information is being added automatically, it must be on the CD, right? Additionally, when I ripped Marc's cover CD, that information was not present in the files obtained. Had I ripped the CD incorrectly? I looked into it though, and it seems that many CD rippers use an online database to find the data to add to the ripped tracks; this data isn't on the CD itself. However, it got me thinking: the CD does have a concept of track numbers, even if no other meta data is present. That data is lost when ripping. Should it not be added back? But at the point that I add that information to the files, am I not already modifying the files? Should I also add back in the other missing meta data while I'm at it? I strongly believe that I shouldn't add missing meta data to music files that I acquire as files. After all, if the meta data was meant to be there, it would already be there. However, the situation is a bit strange with CDs. Transferring the music from CD to digital file is a change of mediums. The meta data is all (or maybe just mostly) there, it's just printed on the CD case insert instead of in the files, as there are no files. Should I copy this information into the files? Adding the cover art will prove problematic, as there's no lossless way to convert the physical cover into a digital image.

I also reconsidered the format for my archive. Because the files do not exist as files on the CD, perhaps the best representation of the original disk for on a file system is a disk image. That idea didn't pan out though, as it turns out that software on the computer can't actually see the data on the disc. Instead, the CD drive reads and interprets the data on the drive, then passes what it finds on to the computer. This means that because each track is sent to the machine separately, it's not possible to view the disc as a whole, so it's not possible to create (or use) a disc image. Worse though, the error correction used when discs are scratched is also performed by the CD drive itself. It's not possible for the computer to know if the data is damaged and had to be repaired! On #Debian-Offtopic, Nemodir recommended Morituri, a CD ripper that asks the drive to read the CD twice and compares the results in an attempt to detect problems with the physical disc. I think I'll start using that to rip CDs and may rerip Marc's cover song CD with it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Secretly-nonfree works and hauntingly beautiful piano music

Day 00409: Tuesday, 2016 April 19

I began the process of setting up email filters with my service provider server-side. My hope is that if I can set up filters that replicate my own in-client searches, I can save a lot of time. For example, I get a lot of spam that's written in Cyrillic characters, so I search for characters that seem to be highly-used in that character set to find spam to delete. Certain of my email addresses have also succeeded in keeping my main email address away from spammers, but because all email addresses lead to the same inbox, that hasn't been good for anything besides searches for spam to delete. Using filters, I've now begun automatically sorting mail sent to those addresses to my spam box as well. Lastly, several political mailing lists agrivatingly send about five emails or each day, which fills up my inbox and prevents me from getting to any of my political mail, as I'm too busy sorting it from personal mail. Filtering that out as well should make keeping up with email actually possible, or so I hope.

I went back to my former place of employment and was able to get one box, though they said that they'd save boxes for me to pick up later. My former boss also offered me my job there back, but I said that the commute was too far, so he jokingly offered me a place to stay with one of the shift leaders. I notice though that he didn't offer to let me stay with him. I came back later, and found that they hadn't actually saved any boxes for me. They had a few that they hadn't flattened yet and gave me those, but the majority had been recycled already.

I found that Helix Prophecy and The White Lie Album, both of which are on Professor Shyguy's USB drive, are nonfree. With those six tracks removed from my music library, I've basically paid fifty dollars for only four USB-drive-exclusive tracks. I am not amused. I had no way to know what was on the drive until I bought it though, so it's not like I could have avoided this.

I started review the albums that I've purchased on Bandcamp, something that I should have started a long time ago. As an experiment, I left three reviews for Fragmentation, as I have three copies of it. It seems that only one review is displayed on the album's purchase page when you do that, and you don't get a choice in which review is used. Furthermore, if you rearrange your collection (for example, I try to keep mine alphabetized), that review will overwrite others for the same album, causing the other reviews to be lost entirely. This means that even if you have multiple of the same album in your collection for some reason, it's not worth leaving multiple reviews to get extra character space. Speaking of which, reviews have a character limit, so when I merged the three reviews, I had to trim two of them and remove the third entirely. It's too bad, I wanted to include a warning about the files on the USB drive, but that was the main part that needed to be cut. I also reviewed a couple of the ambient music albums in my collection. Ambient music isn't so bad in small doses and when you're not having to frantically rush to perform fast-paced work.

I was looking at Woodward's Kickstarted campaign again, and it seems that he was supposed to send a photograph of himself holding a "thank you" note. I didn't see that in the package, but I'll take another look when I get home. It's not like I need this photograph, it was so trivial that I forgot that it was supposed to exist, but it is strange if it's honestly missing. It seems that Josh Woodward is no longer selling individual FLAC files or FLAC albums any more either. If you want his work in FLAC form, you have to order his full bundle that includes all his FLAC files. Furthermore, it seems that he's not selling individual tracks or albums at all any more. I'm a bit confused by this turn of events. It also means that if you want a FLAC file for a new track that he releases, you must purchase the full music bundle, even if you've already purchased it.

I found a new artist that I like on Bandcamp, a pianist that goes by the names Myuu and Myuuji. I especially love the track Don't Die on Me. His work is a bit dark, but it's hauntingly beautiful. I wasn't planning on buying it until after I get home on Sunday, but I just kept playing Don't Die on Me until Bandcamp started showing its guilt trip message about opening my heart/wallet. Because of that message, I would have bought the album tonight, but Bandcamp kept trying to charge me VAT. I'll keep trying tomorrow.

I stumbled upon a useful bug in Bandcamp today. While Bandcamp's server doesn't complain about a dot being used at the end of a domain when loading a page, its JavaScript doesn't seem to work when such a fully-qualified domain name is used. It's stupid that Bandcamp doesn't function without JavaScript, but I can use this bug to make it easier or more difficult to play and purchase music that I link to. For example, I linked to two nonfree works in this weblog entry, but if anyone wants to play or buy that music, they'll need to remove the trailing dot by hand first. It doesn't outright prevent such playing and purchases, but it deters it. For Myuu's work and Shyguy's free work, I omitted the trailing dot, making playback and purchase slightly easier.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A music-purchasing strategy shift

Day 00410: Wednesday, 2016 April 20

I bought Myuu's colective works on Bandcamp today, but upon returning to Bandcamp from PayPal, Bandcamp gave me a 403 error. What in the world? I've never had Bandcamp block me when I use Tor! I tried sending Tor a HUP signal though, and the problem went away. I guess that Bandcamp doesn't like that one exit node, though I'm not sure what exit node that that is. I wonder what happened through that exit node to make Bandcamp ban it.

I received a letter from Marc With a C saying that he's having a clearout sale on some of his vinyl records. He's almost ot of stock on these, and apparently wants to get the remaining few out of his hair. If you purchase Exactly Where I Am, Normal Bias (Remaster), Life's So Hard, This World Is Scary As F**k (Marc censored that, not me), or The Real Live Sound Of Marc With a C in vinyl form by May first, he'll throw in a copy of Pop! Pop! Pop! on vinyl as well. The Real Live Sound Of Marc With a C and Normal Bias (Remaster) come with vinyl-only tracks, but because digitizing them isn't cost-effective or clean, they aren't of any interest to me beyond whimsical "what if he released digital copies of these tracks?" thoughts. Life's So Hard also contains a vinyl-only bonus track, but i have one of those large plastic discs in my closet already alongside This World Is Scary As F**k and a two-track record that appears to be nameless. If you're going to take Marc up on this offer (and don't want to buy all five before you lose your chance), I think that the This World Is Scary As F**k is potentially the most fruitful. The description still mentions the digital-only bonus albums, which may or may not still be available if you purchase that album.

Later, I went through Marc's catalog to put his albums on my wish list. I found that I couldn't put Actual Bubblegum Pop on my wish list though, as Marc refuses to accept payment for that one. I downloaded it gratis, but then I went on a gratis music binge, downloading several albums from Marc and other artists that I could (and likely will) eventually purchase. While putting the rest of Marc's catalog on my wish list, I ran across The Early Stuff CD, a CD-only work that contains both tracks that are available for digital download and tracks that aren't. I should have bought that instead of Exactly Where I Am in August! I like Exactly Where I Am, but I don't need a physical copy of it. In any case, I sort of regret hastily purchasing Myuu's collective works now, and I'd like to place an order for this CD when I get home, both to get the CD-only tracks and to support Marc and his sale without actually involving any vinyl. I've also thought about it though, and I think that I'm paying too much for music. My initial plan was to pay five dollars for each album that didn't have a price tag on it, but due to an PayPal being a pain and me being sloppy in testing, I ended up accidentally paying double what I had intended to. I was frustrated at first, but I ended up making a habit of paying ten dollars for each name-your-price album to support artists more. Digital downloads take less money to produce though, so it shouldn't be a problem to pay less, especially given my financial situation. I'm also starting to leave positive reviews on each album that I buy, and maybe that's worth something as well. I also pay too much to Josh Woodward, so it's not like I'm not supporting the arts.

Speaking of music, I got Cyrus to check the mail yesterday. He told me that he'd check daily and I asked him about it two days ago, but it seems that he had forgotten and that my message had gotten lost due to our faulty modem. The package from Brandt Cooley has arrived! Based on the feel of the package, it contains both the CD and the USB drive. I never got the shipping refund that Shyguy had promised, but at least he didn't pay to ship two packages when one would suffice. If you have two things to send someone, it seems illogical to send it as two separate packages.

Through a lot of the day, I had two songs stuck in my head simultaneously, which was a strangeness that I've never experienced before. The main song was Myuu's Don't Die on Me, of course, but I never could pinpoint what the second song (a chiptune song by Professor Shyguy). I thought that it was New Treasure Seeker, but that wasn't quite right. Every time that I'd try to listen to Shyguy's work to find the song, it'd drive the chiptune song out of my head for quite a while, so as I had work to do, it wasn't a good use of my time to work on this and I gave up quickly.

I went to my former place of employment again for boxes. I was able to get quite a few this time, and it should be all that I need for now. On the way there, I went through a dead-end street leading to a field that many people cut through as a shortcut on foot. On that dead-end street, there were three mail carriers, each with their own mail-carrying car. Why would three mail carriers be needed for one small dead-end street?

It seems that this week is my father's vacation week or something. He's been around the house all day. I was waiting for him to leave so I could vacuum, as my mother wanted me to stay under his radar, but I haven't even gotten one room vacuumed yet. I need to actually get started on this. I emailed my mother to let her know of the situation and that I planned to start vacuuming soon because of the limited amount of time. She replied that she wanted me to instead wait until Friday, when my father would have to pick up Cyrus and Vanessa, leaving a four-hour window in which he'd be away and I could vacuum without his knowledge. Really!? A four-hour window to vacuum an entire house that's filled with junk? I'm going to have to cut major corners to pull that off. Even more stuff will need to be boxed too, in order to make it mobile enough to vacuum under most piles of junk. I likely won't have time to vacuum under several things as well. This sucks, and it's a stupid plan, but whatever. I'll do as I've been instructed. I'll spend my time until Friday boxing things in preparation.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

PCMan File Manager

Day 00411: Thursday, 2016 April 21

Boxing work continues today as I wait for Friday to arrive.

I've had this problem with file managers. For as long as I can remember, seemingly every graphical file manager I've used has been unable to sort files in a reasonable order. I define a "reasonable order" as having two characteristics. First, every character in the file name is considered individually. The sorting of files is done in such a way that the order is predictable when looking at one character at a time, not groups of characters. Second, each possible character is treated as a different character than every other possible character. If a file manager sorts three files into the order 1.txt, 2.txt, 10.txt, it is violating the first rule, as it's grouping numeric characters and sorting based on the perceived numeric value. Note that I don't even care what order the file manager sorts characters into; 2.txt can come first or last in the list. It just can't come between two files that begin with the same character. File managers that ignore non-alphanumeric characters when sorting also violate this rule. Case insensitivity breaks the second rule. I don't care if the sorting order is "A, B, a, b" or "A, a, B, b", but upper-case and lower-case letters must not be mixed. Every few months, I try again to get Thunar to sort files reasonably and I try to find other graphical file managers that can be made to sort files reasonably.

I set aside a bit of time to work with this problem today. As always, my first attempts to resolve the problem were put towards trying to get Thunar to behave. By setting the bash environmental variable LC_COLLATE to C, you can get Thunar to sort in a case-sensitive manor. Note though that Thunar's actual setting for enabling case sensitivity doesn't work though! As usual, I couldn't find a way to get Thunar to quit grouping numeric characters, so I moved on and tried other file managers. I kind of skipped over the common file managers used as default by other desktop environments, as I've tried them so many times before and gotten nowhere. The first file manager that I came across today was Gentoo, a file manager that shares its name with an operating system distribution. Gentoo does the annoying digit-grouping thing, but this can be disabled by setting the sorting algorithm to "URI". The problem with this sorting algorithm is that it treats characters that aren't URI-compatible as three characters: a percent sign and two hexadecimal digits. As it should be encoding the percent signs in the same way, this is only a problem in theory though; it's just a method of implementation as far as my purposes go. In practice, this just means that all URI-incompatible characters will be sorted to similar locations.

While I did find a working file manager on the first try this time, I decided to keep looking. Gentoo sorts files reasonably, but that's not all that a file manager can do. Gentoo is a two-pane file manager, which gives me the impression that I can't open an arbitrary number of windows and have them interact. Even if I can, it'd be a bit clunky. Furthermore, Thunar can integrate with MTP so I can use it to manage files on my mobile as well, but Gentoo lacks this option. Next, I tried GNOME commander, but it has the usual problem where it groups digits in file names. Konqueror not only mishandles digits by grouping them, but also ignores LC_COLLATE and offers no way to enable case sensitivity. Xfe seems slightly clunky, but it's nicer than Gentoo! If LC_COLLATE is set to C, files are displayed in a reasonable order, including files with digits in their names. It too lacks MTP support though. Worker can't correctly display non-ASCII characters in file names correctly, so the names of my ~/Elŝutoj and ~/Ŝablonoj directories are displayed mangled. Needing to get back to work, I set up my system to use Xfe and called it good for now.

A bit later though, I mentioned trying a bunch of file managers in #Volatile. Somenub said that I should give PCMan File Manager a try. I'd skipped that file manager today because it's the one from LXDE and LXDE is a bit light on features. I gave it a try upon recommendation though, and PCMan File Manager might just be the perfect file manager for me. By default, PCMan File Manager doesn't sort files correctly, but after setting LC_COLLATE to C and turning off the "Ignore Name Case" option, everything falls into place. PCMan File Manager looks and act a lot like Thunar, though it will take some time to get used to the subtle differences. This file manager even handles MTP! Unlike Thunar though, PCMan File Manager doesn't use a consistent order for displaying files available over MTP. Simply refreshing the directory listing can result in an entirely different file order. My best guess is that PCMan File Manager displays files in whatever order Replicant provides and that Replicant inherited a bug from Android that prevents there from being a consistent order. Thunar on the other hand ignores the order provided over MTP to keep files displayed in an organized fashion. I can deal with seeing my mobiles files in an inconsistent order if it means that my local files are displayed in a reasonable order. This new file manager opens new tabs instead of new windows when opening files from the directory menu on Xfce's panel, but this is easily fixable by telling Xfce to use PCMan File Manager's --new-win flag. PCMan File Manager can run the desktop too if you run pcmanfm --desktop, though you then need to set your wallpaper again, as it has no way to know what wallpaper you used with your old desktop manager. I went through my file system and found what I think is my old wallpaper.

I added export LC_COLLATE=C and pcmanfm --desktop to my X session file (and removed /home/yst/i2p/i2prouter start while I was at it because I no longer use I2P), but that royally messed things up. With that configuration, Xfce doesn't start until PCMan File Manager finishes running. Of course, it doesn't finish running on its own as it's supposed to last until the end of the session, and with only a desktop manager running, there's no clear way to log out. Opening up a command prompt is difficult, and I'm not actually sure how I made it work, as the option is usually greyed out in this state. I commented that line out from TTY1, removed it once I got to my desktop, and added pcmanfm --desktop instead to the list of software that Xfce starts at the beginning of the session. Now it's involved in a race condition with Xfdesktop, where whichever one executes last wins. I can't prevent Xfce from starting Xfdesktop, either. I'll figure something out when I have time.

When I went to get groceries for today, my father unexpectedly rode by on his motorcycle as I turned a corner. By the time I realized that he was there, it might have been too late, but I turned around and went back to try to minimize the risk.

The modem has gone down again at home. It's aggravating knowing that it's down and that there's nothing that I can do to bring it back up.

My thumb is healing up better now that it's not constantly wet. Being wet all the time before seems to have led to too much clotting material being used. The scab's way too thick and doesn't bend enough for me to easily use my thumb. I've peeled it off to let a more regular scab form. My shin is also sore for some reason, though I have no idea what I've done to it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Vacuuming and and dealing with a cURL developer

Day 00412: Friday, 2016 April 22

My father left fairly early today, so I got to work on vacuuming right away. While my mother was convinced that four hours would be enough time to get all the vacuuming done, it wasn't even close. He ended up away most of the day, so I had a lot more time than expected, and I still barely got most of the vacuuming done that I planned to. I did have to leave half of my mother's closet unvacuumed because of all the shoes, the uncarpeted floors (figuring that I could sweep those floors later), and my sisters' room (as I still haven't had time to clean that room). I'll work on sweeping and cleaning the final room tomorrow.

Discussion about cURL's bug began again today when one of the cURL developers said that he planned to document the behavior instead of fixing it, also saying that Web browsers don't follow the standard either. I think that our conversation speaks for itself, which for the record, went as follows:

badger:

I'm aiming for just documenting the situation as the discussion in httpbis didn't go anywhere, the browsers don't follow the specs (as mentioned) and I don't see any benefit in changing curl to start doing so.

Y-st:

If you want to document it and leave the code in cURL alone, that's fine. It's a bit misleading to say that Web browsers aren't following the standard though.

Most Web browsers aren't *currently* following the standard, but I did manage to get the Qt developers to fix the bug in their networking code, so any Web browser that relies on Qt for this sort of thing will be fixed upon the next Qt release (Qt might have even released a new version by now, I'm not sure). The GNOME developers have acknowledged the bug as well, believing it to be in glib. They aren't acting as quickly as the Qt developers, but a fix is likely coming at some point, so Web browsers dependent on glib will likely also end up fixed. Likewise, Google's known about this issue for a while as part of a larger issue in their code, and it sounds like a patch for that problem is in the works for Chromium/Chrome too. From the sounds of it, Firefox might not fix the problem (despite already having a patch for it) and I'm not sure that Microsoft knows that Internet Explorer has the problem, but many Web browsers are likely going to be following the standard in the nearish future.

badger:

I was referring to the major browsers. Chrome, IE, Safari, Firefox. The Qt HTTP stack is not used in any of those.

As mentioned already, I opened a discussion about this on the httpbis mailing list and there was no particular interest in the HTTP community to work on this.

Google's known about this issue for a while as part of a larger issue in their code, and it sounds like a patch for that problem is in the works for Chromium

Link?

Finally, you're working very hard to "fix" this with no particular use case that shouts for a fix. If you would be able to show a few different places where this causes a problem in real life right now, I think I and others would be more inclined to work on changing things.

Y-st:

<https://bugs.chromium.org./p/chromium/issues/detail?id=496472> says:

This is a tracking bug for the clean-up tasks, in case anyone wants to grab it / yell at me:

That means that it's not a bug report, but rather a note from one of the developers saying that this needs to be fixed. It also says:

The only usage of this is for validating that the QUIC SNI information is well-formed. QUIC SNI follows the rules of TLS's SNI (RFC 6066), which dictates the use of IDNA A-Labels without the trailing '.'

... and:

4) Ensure it's normalized to strip off any trailing '.' that may have been in the URL host as a DNS resolver hint (if sending) or that it doesn't have a trailing '.' if handling as a server (this is handled by #3)

It sounds to me like they have admitted a need to fix the bug, but some parts of that bug page are too technical for me to understand, so I could be wrong.

I think that a lot of places don't use the dotted host name for one of three reasons: they don't think that their users are tech-savvy enough to add a dot, they don't realize that the dot is even an option, or because Web clients aren't handling it properly, so it can't be reliably used yet. (There's also the personal preference crowd. Some people begin their domains with "www.", some don't. The same applies to the trailing dot.) Website owners shouldn't be forced to choose the undotted version of their domain for canonization just because Web clients are too buggy to handle it. I think that this is part of why the XHTML Content-Type header still hasn't seen the adoption that it deserves: Most versions of Internet Explorer can't handle it.

I'm going to be setting up my canonization to use the dotted version of the domain, as it is the absolute form, the fully-qualified domain name. To redirect from the dotted version to the non-dotted version seems incorrect, as a non-dotted domain can and in some cases is resolved against a local domain. While I respect the decision of some websites to canonize to the undotted form, it seems like this should be the decision of the website owner, not the decision of faulty Web clients that choose to be buggy. I doubt that cURL will be an issue on my website, as my site's too small for cURL use to be likely.

However, choosing not to follow standards seems like a bad idea. You say that you don't want to follow the standards because most clients don't follow it, but that very inertia is the problem. Many of them might also not be fixing their bugs because none of the other clients follow the standard. "Why should we follow the standards if no one else does?" Instead of choosing to be part of the solution, you choose to be part of what prevents standards from being, well, standard.

badger:

Standards aren't there to be followed blindly. They should be there for a purpose. Right now, following the standards break more things than holding off. Compatibility with "the browsers" and "not breaking stuff" is more important to me than basically anything else.

Y-st:

You think that I'm trying to blindly follow standards, and I get that, but I think that you're blindly following what other Web client developers are doing. If you want to leave the bug in place, I have no problem with that. It's your software, not mine.

However, you've yet to mention even one use case that this fix would break. You mentioned Yahoo! and sites like it that are hosted on servers that can't handle the trailing dot, but those same sites aren't redirecting to a trailing-dot domain, linking to their trailing-dot version, or interacting with trailing dots in any way. Websites that don't use the trailing dot can continue not using the trailing dot and cURL will continue to successfully download pages from them.

By all means, if you think that cURL should strip the trailing dot, have it continue doing that. Just please don't blame other Web clients or Web servers for your decision. It is your decision and your decision alone. (Well, and the decision of any other cURL developers, but not the decision of developers of other projects.) If other developers were adding DRM that prevented their Web clients from being copied, would you do that too?

I think that badger's logic on this is very flawed. I don't think that I can actually make any progress with this, but at least when people complain about cURL not working to retrieve pages from my website, I can point to documented evidence that not only is this a cURL bug, not a bug in my website, but that I tried my best to get the bug fixed to no avail.

Someone wanted to talk to me over OTR on IRC today, though I hadn't set that up yet. The problem was that on HexChat, setting up OTR was too much of a pain to do. I forget the exact issue, but it involved doing something that I am unwilling to do; perhaps compile from source then install the compiled software in a system directory? I only use software that I've compiled from source in my own directories, reserving system directories for use by packaged software. I'm no longer on HexChat though, I'm on WeeChat. I simply hadn't gotten around to installing OTR software for WeeChat. I responded that it would take me a bit to get the OTR software installed, but he/she kept sending OTR session-starting requests anyway. Installing otr.py was easy enough, but it didn't work. Installing python-potr from my package manager got otr.py to start functioning though, so I was able to get the OTR session started myself. After doing so, I found out that the other user was on Tails, and that Tails' default configuration prevents users from sending messages without first establishing a secure channel. Those repeated attempts to initiate an OTR session were made by the client each time that the user tried to send an unencrypted message to me. Who knew?

The user and I spoke for quite a while, and one thing that came up was CopperheadOS, a free mobile operating system based on Android. It's code is more up-to-date than Replicant's, but like Replicant, only runs on a select few devices, none of which are my Samsung GT-I9300. Supposedly, all the code is free, but it's said that Google integration is optional. If it's optional, that means it's possible, but Google service integration requires proprietary software. That means that either the user must install the Google proprietary components separately from the system (in which case saying that integration is an option is misleading) or the system contains those proprietary components, but they aren't active unless the user turns them on (in which case the system isn't fully free, as it contains proprietary components). As it doesn't run on my device, I'm going to give the project time to mature until my device breaks down, at which point I'll look more into the freedom of this system and make a choice between it and Replicant for my next device.

The lack of spam and political email in my inbox has been nice. It needs a bit of fine-tuning still and even then there will be things that the filters cannot catch, but once I'm caught up on everything else that I need to get done, I think that I stand a chance of actually catching up with email processing.

Wowaname was speaking in Arabic characters and mentioned Unifont to someone that wasn't able to see those glyphs. I could see the Arabic characters, but there's a lot of glyphs that I can't see, so I installed it myself. Unfortunately, it's not a fixed-width font, so esoteric characters now disrupt the gridlike arrangement of characters on my screen, but at least I can actually see those characters! "𐅯", "🔮", and "🕹" now display as they should.

Our modem has gone down again, and this time, only my mother is around to fix it. I like the odds better when Vanessa and Cyrus are around as well. Not only are there then three people that might notice the downed connection, but our mother doesn't spend as much time online as those two do, so she's less likely to notice it and it'll take longer before the connectivity is restored.

Cyrus reported to me that our father knows that I'm around. He did see me yesterday. Also though, he's asked Cyrus to give me his Wi-Fi password.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

CD-Text, Quod Libet, MP3 file inconsistency, and a battle of wills

Day 00413: Saturday, 2016 April 23

I'm about to have a second CD album, and most likely, both of my CD albums don't/won't have meta data. I've decided to look into meta data in case I decide that adding my own is in fact the correct approach. Both FLAC files and Vorbis files use Vorbis comments, so I read up on what tags I'd need to be adding. As it turns out, there's a limit to the number of tags that you can have in Vorbis comments, but you can give them arbitrary names as long as they conform to the very liberal name syntax. This makes them much more extensible than ID3 comments, but also means that I have no structure with which to work with. There are several basic tags that I want to include, but beyond that, what else should I add? If I were using a restrictive tag set such as ID3 that only allowed certain tags, the answer would be obvious: add every available tag. Maybe I should use only the meta data used by my mobile, minus the cover art. It's a very arbitrary set of tags, but I don't know what else to go with. I considered these tags for use:

track number: included on CD, so most important tag to use
album cover: used by the mobile, but probably best left empty to conserve space
title: used by the mobile
album name: used by the mobile for sorting albums
album artist: used by the mobile for sorting albums
track artist: used by the mobile
lyrics: neat, but probably not included in CD insert, not used by the mobile
genre: used by the mobile, but probably not included in CD insert

Maybe I should just try to include as much information (aside from the cover art) as I can get from the CD insert. If the information doesn't seem to relate to much, I could just put it in a "Comment" tag.

Perhaps if meta data isn't included on the CDs though, it should just be left out of the ripped files. As it turns out, audio CDs can have meta data using CD-Text. If CD-Text isn't used for the CD, maybe the correct choice is to not use meta data, as it's similar to the situation in which WAVE files or metaless FLAC/Vorbis files are provided. In the case of those files, meta data was deliberately left out and should remain missing. K3b and cd-info from libcdio-utils are supposed to be able to read CD-Text from audio CDs, but the audio CDs that I have access to here in our former residence don't seem to have it. It could be because the CDs were manufactured not too long after the standard was put in place (many even came out before the standard), but an article I read about CD burning says that not many CDs use it. It seems like maybe even modern CDs aren't likely to have this much-needed meta data.

Wowaname knows about the issues that I'm having with the cURL developers, and showed me how real developers can handle things. She's got a problem with Atheme IRC services, so she told the developers on IRC. One of them reported it in the project's bug tracker, flagging it as needing discussion. Another developer came along and said how does this need discussion? it's a bug... fix it. and removed the flag about it needing discussion. It's a bug. Fix it. There no need to discuss if buggy behavior should be maintained! If only the cURL developers saw it that way.

I took some time to try to fix the sound output issue in Quod Libet again. It's a nice and simple music player, but since installing cepo's operating system, it hasn't functioned. I've assumed that this is due to a missing package in the Debian 8 default install, but it's a bit strange, as Quod Libet itself was installed by default. Since then, every once in a while, I try to figure out what that missing package is. I found instructions for getting it working in an old version of Ubuntu, so I tried installing the packages mentioned. That didn't work. I ended up paying a visit to #QuodLibet in hopes of maybe getting somewhere. JanC tried to be very helpful, but was as lost as I was. After quite a bit of checking various things that didn't pan out, I happened to run a search for "gstreamer" in my packages. I found that while gstreamer0.10-alsa was installed, gstreamer1.0-alsa was not. After installing that, Quod Libet was able to play music properly. Yay! This wasn't of huge concern, as I usually use my mobile for music and I could always use VLC Media Player to play music after navigating to it in my file system, but having an actual working music manager on newdawn.local. is nice. JanC said that she didn't know why she hadn't thought of that sooner, and recommended using gstreamer1.0-pulseaudio instead. Purging the former and installing the latter, Quod Libet continued to play.

Speaking of Quod Libet, I accidentally stumbled upon a new display mode for my albums. This mode is much nicer, displaying a customizable label along with the album's artwork in a list on the left. Additionally, I tracked down another discrepancy between Ex Falso's view of albums and Replicant's view of albums. In addition to Replicant choosing one version of a given MP3 file's ID3 meta data over the other with no visible pattern as to which is chosen, Ex Falso, which uses the same tag-reading library as Quod Libet, reads the ID3 tags a bit differently than Replicant and Kid3. The tag that Replicant and Kid3 treats as the "album artist" is instead treated by Quod Libet and Ex Falso as the "performer". There is a very big difference in both the sorting and the meaning of these tags. The album artist is simply the one that put the album together, and may not have even performed any of the tracks. The corresponding tag allows separate albums to be considered by the machine to be separate while still allowing work by multiple artists to remain on the same album if that is indeed the intention. It acts on the assumption that one artist won't release multiple albums by the same title, which would be a pretty stupid thing for them to do. The performer though is obviously the one that performed in the recorded track, and shouldn't have any effect on sorting. What this discrepancy means is that Quod Libet and Ex Falso will never see an "album artist" tag on any MP3 files, so they cannot be used to sort my MP3 files if I want the sorting to match that of my mobile. I swear, MP3 files are a pain. FLAC and Vorbis files are treated in a much more consistent manor, not to mention the free de facto codecs for them, the lack of patents, and the better sound quality.

I got the sweeping done today, but I spent too much time dealing with music file research and debugging Quod Libet, so I didn't get any work done on the girls' bedroom. I'll need to hurry and finish that tomorrow.

As I was going to bed, I noticed that wowaname was in some fight with KindOne in #Volatile. I have no idea what started the fight, but wowaname wanted KindOne to leave and KindOne wanted wowaname to ban him from the server using a K-line. Wowaname was refusing to use technical measures to make KindOne leave, instead insisting that KindOne needed to leave of his own accord. Wowaname dropped her server operator status and her channel operator status, ostensibly to show that she had no intention of backing up her verbal banishment with the technical implementation, but after a while, she wanted to try flooding KindOne off the network. She couldn't do this though, as the channel user limit was set too low to prevent such abuse by others. Without her channel operator status, she couldn't do it, so she asked for someone, anyone, to raise the user limit; about half of the in the channel are channel operators. I was not going to get involved in this though, especially considering the fact that I didn't even know what the fight was really about. I'm not against KindOne, and raising the user limit would have been an act of aggression against KindOne. JorHec eventually removed the user limit altogether, after which a spam battle between wowaname and KindOne ensued. Wowaname next wanted her operator status back, but again, I was staying out of it. I harbor no ill will towards KindOne. By this point, I was far too tired to continue watching this madness, so I went to bed. I already should have been asleep and I have a lot to get done tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

SHYDRIVE and The Early Stuff CD

Day 00414: Sunday, 2016 April 24

I didn't get as much cleaning done as I'd hoped in the girls' bedroom. My mother seemed fine with the amount that I'd gotten done around the house, but I know if I'd put in a bit more effort, I'd have gotten more done. That place is so draining though, and I didn't have a proper pillow or blanket to sleep with, so I wasn't getting as much rest as I should have.

We stopped at more second hand stores in Springfield before picking up Vanessa and Cyrus, then we headed home. I was anxious to take a look at the package from Brandt Cooley, but we spent the remaining daylight hours gathering bullet shells in the hills.

Once we arrived at home, I found that the package from Brant contained both the CD and the USB drive. The CD didn't arrive as quickly as I thought that it would have if he'd sent it right away, so i was actually hoping that he'd decided to save on postage by sending the two together. There's no need to pay the post office any more than you need to to get your items shipped. The CD case looks interesting, but I can't get a good look tonight. I can't see well, as Cyrus has decided that we should use dim solar-powered lights in our bedroom. I certainly wouldn't want to discourage an attempt to do things in a more environmentally-conscious manor. I'll need to take a better look by daylight tomorrow. Both Marc's CD and Shyguy's CD lack CD-Text; or perhaps my CD drive simply can't read it. I suspect the former though. Morituri is trying to reach the Internet in order to retrieve meta data to use, but it's failing to perform a rip on Professor Shyguy's Fragmentation. I'm not even going to try to debug that though, as if the tool is going to try to use meta data taken from the Internet, it's of no use to me. The cd-text command shows a lack of meta data on the CDs though, which may be the cause of Morituri trying to get it from elsewhere. I'll just rip the CDs using drag-and-drop and hope that the bits aren't damaged because the CDs are brand new and without scratches when I perform the rips. I put in an order for a third CD, The Early Stuff CD, which will likely also not have meta data. I'll probably spend tomorrow adding meta data to the first two CDs. I should really avoid buying more music for a while now, I've put too much money into my collection in this past short while.

The new USB drive is a bit different than the last one. The data inside seems to be the same save for the fact that it contains Instrumentation and has a new drive name. Instead of the drive having the generic name DISK_IMG, it's now called SHYDRIVE. I'll need to check to see if all the other files are the same later, but for now, I just backed the data from the drive up so that I could wipe it. A quick glance through shows that many of the same songs that were missing from the original drive are missing from this one too though. The SHYDRIVE looks more professional than the last one. Instead of a tiny plastic fragment being glued to the inner drive to allow extraction using one's finger nail, the drive's electronic component is curved and needs no extra grip. The catch though is that the drive no longer tucks away fully, so it's more easily damaged and doesn't fit inside the Game Boy game protecting case as well. The drive also uses a different Game Boy game shell than the one that I sent back. My hope is that Brandt plans to disassemble it later to reuse the case and that to speed things along, he just sent me a different drive that he'd already assembled. After all, if he's not going to reuse the case and the USB drive is defective, it was a waste to send it back. It was an interesting novelty item. The SHYDRIVE is also only a thirty-two gigabyte drive instead of the previous sixty-four gigabyte drive. I now suspect that this is the reason that the drive's purchase page is inconsistent. The old drives, one of which I purchased, were sixty-four gigabyte drives. However, when found unreliable, Brandt started using different drives, this time thirty-two gigabytes in size. He must not have fully updated the product-listing pages. With that in mind, it seems like it's a rip off to replace the drive with a smaller one. People who paid for the initial one did so with the knowledge that they were getting the larger size of drive! This is a bit annoying, but I will ignore it. This was never about the physical drive anyway, it was about the files that the drive contained, files that weren't available for download. Files that turned out to be only three in number. I did some minor testing, adding one large ZIP file to the drive, removing the drive, and reconnecting to see if the file was still there. That went well, so formatted the drive as ext2, then started transferring the original files back onto it from the backup. That process won't be complete tonight, so I'll check on it in the morning.

Tonight, I get to sleep in a bed with a working pillow and a full-sized blanket. Perfect, I'm very tired.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Evolution is leaking DNS requests!

Day 00415: Monday, 2016 April 25

The SHYDRIVE appears to function normally! The lower storage capacity makes me reluctant to use this drive to store music archives though, so I've set it aside for now. PCMan File Manager doesn't seem to shut down my external hard drive after dismounting it like Thunar does. I'm not sure if this is a feature, allowing the drive to be removed safely or remounted, or a bug, preventing the drive from actually being dismounted correctly.

I am trying to back up my music collection in the most accurate way possible. To me, that means that if an artist provided WAVE files, which aren't able to contain meta data, I don't back up any meta data. Likewise, if the artist provides FLAC, Vorbis, or MP3 files without meta data or with incomplete meta data, I don't add any missing data. To add the missing meta data would be to archive a modified version of the file, not the original file. However, I have two CDs to archive as well. It's my understanding that it's not possible with current technology to make a disk image of an audio CD, which is what I'd consider to be the most accurate representation of the music. Instead, the music must be ripped into files. When doing this, no meta data is available, as the CDs lack meta data. In fact, even the track numbers are lost. The CDs do contain track numbers by design, so it would make sense to convert the ripped WAVE files into FLAC files, then add the track number meta data. The fact is though, the music data has had to switch between two incompatible digital formats, one of which in a way actually exists outside of digital data. I've decided to add some of that data back in, if for no other reason, for my own ease. I found that Kid3 doesn't allow adding of arbitrary tags as is allowed in Vorbis comments. Instead, a discreet number of tags are available to choose from, some of which are validated against some syntax and the tag value is thrown out if it doesn't conform. I've decided to copy all text from the CDs and their cases into plain text files to include in the archives that I'm building of the CDs and add only a few limited tags to the actual FLAC files. I've added "Title", "Artist", "Album", "Track Number", and "Album Artist" tags, all of which are known to be used by Replicant. I've also added "Website" and "LICENSE" tags, just in case my files end up in someone else's hands. As for cover art, I've made no attempt to digitize the album covers. The fact is, I only have tow options for such digitization. I could use my mobile's blurry camera, but the results would be, well, blurry. I could use my mother's scanner, but that scanner isn't free software compatible, and I'd hate to introduce some artifact from a scanner that I can't actually endorse, especially if there's an easy way to find out what scanner was used (I'm not sure if there's an easy way or not). Fragmentation's product page has a photograph of the front and back of the CD case, so I included both photographs in my archive. Marc's cover CD never had a product page, so it was a bit trickier. I grabbed the photograph of Marc from his short autobiography on Bandcamp to use as the cover art. That's far from cannon at for the album, but it's good enough for now.

While trying to examine the insert of the Fragmentation CD, I broke a small brittle spot on the case. I also see a small chip that I'm not sure I had anything to do with. Why are CD cases so fragile? For that matter, CDs get scratched up way too easily as well. Music downloads are so much better. They aren't subject to physical damage as much, they are way easier to back up and/or duplicate, and there's no shipping to wait for. Downloads take minutes or hours, not days!

I checked on the package from Josh Woodward, and the promised photograph is indeed missing. I should examine the scratch paper that he did send later, but I don't have time today. He's also neglected to send the FLAC so far.

The Early Stuff CD is now shown as being sold out. This could mean either of two things. It could mean that my purchase caused Marc to notice that the album was still shown as being available when he doesn't sell them any more, in which case he'll likely send a refund in the near future. The alternative is that I've purchased the actual last copy of the CD. Again, digital music downloads are so much better than physical copies. Physical copies are so finite!

It seems that I received a letter from my primary health care provider while I was in Springfield saying that they've changed which office that they want me to go to one of their closer clinics instead of the one off on the far side of the city. I didn't make any move to request this, they did it on their own, but I'm happy with the decision. My mother thinks that it's still too far, but it's well within walking range, let alone biking range. I've also received my final paycheck for my last job. I should go deposit that when I have time.

The cURL developers have closed the bug report pertaining to their invalid stripping of trailing dots on fully-qualified domain names and have documented the bug as a feature. I failed to get them to fix the problem, but no one can say that I didn't try.

Evolution has been failing to connect to mail servers all day, claiming that it can't reach the servers as long as I'm offline. I've been online most of the day though, and other applications reach the Internet just fine. I finally debugged the situation at the end of the day, and it seems to have been a combination of two problems. First, Bind9 somehow crashed. I'm not clear on what happened, but I suspect that it has to do with the modem going down, like was happening with the Tor crashes. Second, Evolution is leaking DNS requests! With the DNS server down, it gave the illusion that there was no Internet connection. If Evolution was using Tor properly though, the crashed DNS server wouldn't have been a problem.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

One of five!?

Day 00416: Tuesday, 2016 April 26

I biked out to to the store to get some potato-based pasta. That stuff is delicious with marinara!

I received a letter from Marc saying that my copy of The Early Stuff CD has shipped - and that it's the last of its kind. It seems that I'm helping Marc clear out his inventory after all. I still have to agree with what I said yesterday though. I much prefer digital downloads and the fact that they're not so finite. I also have to wonder about just how finite these CDs are. According to the product page, five people have bought a digital copy of Human Slushy and/or a physical copy of The Early Stuff CD. In theory, that means that at most, there are five of this CD. Why would there be so few? I can only hope that Marc sold most of these CDs outside of Bandcamp and that there are actually a fair number of them. I've taken another look through Marc's catalog, and one of his albums that I've seen before caught my eye: HRG - Vol. 1. I've never known what "HRG" means, but now I think that this is the "lost" "Hey Rape Girl!" EP that comes on The Early Stuff CD. ("Lost" is in quotes not because Marc said that it was lost, but because I thought that it was lost.) The CD also contains "bonus live tracks from the 2003 era", so I still anxiously await its arrival.

I looked through the job listings at the temp agency, and it seems that they've reapplied me for one that I'd previously been turned down for. If they're going to reapply me for jobs as they open back up, it should speed up my job search. I've also applied for two more jobs.

Cyrus showed me a supposedly tuition-free university! I'll have to look into it once I finish catching up on some other work.

Josh Woodward announced the release of Addressed to the Stars via email, but he still hasn't sent the FLAC files that he promised. I might need to write to him about this at some point, but I think that I'll wait for now.

My mother says that we should host a garage sale this upcoming weekend. I'm considering trying to sell my CDs and especially my vinyl records. I won't offer much of a discount on them though, so I don't expect that they'll sell. If they do sell, it would spread the artists' work a bit while also netting me funds to get more music (or to recover a bit from what I've already put into my collection).

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to remove the link to the university.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm considering switching to LXDE.

Day 00417: Wednesday, 2016 April 27

Xfce doesn't offer a way to disable Xfdesktop and PCMan File Manager is working well for me. LXDE may have improved since I last tried it. After all, PCMan File Manager is native to LXDE. I might try it again soon. I've also come to the realization that the reason that dragging a file from the desktop to a directory displayed in Thunar copies the file instead of moving it could have something to do with the fact that the desktop manager and the file manager aren't the same application. The two applications probably aren't perfectly calibrated for this sort of interaction, and as the bug exists in the way that the two interact, not in one of the applications individually, it's much easier to overlook. If Thunar was in charge of both the desktop and file management, dragging from the desktop would be no different than dragging from a directory displayed in a window.

IANA hassled wowaname about her whois details not being accurate. She had a valid email address, but not a valid postal address. I agreed to allow her to use me as a proxy, using my address instead of hers. The condition on this was that she use her own valid telephone number, so that I wouldn't get in trouble for invalid contact information. There's a reason that I don't use gTLDs. Anyway, Web Listings Inc. decided to send her postal spam, so it arrived on my house. They want wowaname to pay $85 USD per year to get afsadgsdcgdcfgefcasfcascfsadf.com. listed in search engines. Seriously? They obviously haven't taken a look at the website, and probably aven't even taken a look at the domain. I'm unsure why she even registered that monstrosity, but I doubt that it'll ever be useful.

Wolf put into words something that I needed to hear today, though he didn't say it to me:

@Wolf and astrid I understand getting trolled here hurts sometimes, at times opal makes me want to shed a tear so I go afk and go somewhere else for a bit, this server will always be mean to people from time to time and today its your turn to play bitch
@opal ♥ thanks wolf ♥
@opal ♥ beautiful words ♥
@Wolf i speak the truth
@Wolf lol
@Yst I always wondered what it was. I could never find a pattern to the attacks.

I need to keep in mind that wowaname (opal) is a troll. She likes to cause problems sometimes, people don't have to *do* anything to set her off necessarily.

I've applied for one more job with the temp agency today. I think that the temp agency is my best bet for getting a short-term job to fill the space between now and when we move. I don't really have time for a full-length job right now.

*UPDATE (2016-04-28)*: When I first wrote this entry, I used the duel pronoun "he/she" to refer to Wolf. I didn't know Wolf's preferred pronoun at the time. Wolf has taken offense to this and wants to assert that he is in fact male. This entry has been amended to reflect that. My apologies, no offense was meant.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My first day back on LXDE

Day 00418: Thursday, 2016 April 28

I've installed LXDE, so I'll be using that for a while; just until I can remember why I don't like LXDE and go crawling back to Xfce as I always do. I always have problems when I install multiple desktops. The problem is that I can never get the second desktop removed. You can purge the initial main package that you installed, but stupidly, it doesn't remove all the packages that it pulled in. To do that, you need a list of every package that you installed. In case the need arises, this is what I ended up installing:

yst@newdawn.hn.y.st.:~$ sudo aptitude install lxde
[sudo] password for yst: 
The following NEW packages will be installed:
  alsamixergui clipit galculator gksu gnome-mplayer gnome-system-tools 
  gpicview gtk2-engines{a} leafpad libgda-5.0-4{a} libgda-5.0-common{a} 
  libgksu2-0{a} libgmlib1{a} libgmtk1{a} libgmtk1-data{a} libgtop2-7{a} 
  libgtop2-common{a} libmusicbrainz3-6{a} libobrender29{a} libobt2{a} 
  liboobs-1-5{a} libuser1{a} libxdo3{a} lxappearance lxappearance-obconf 
  lxde lxde-common lxde-core lxde-icon-theme lxinput lxpanel{a} 
  lxpanel-data{a} lxrandr lxsession{a} lxtask{a} lxterminal menu{a} 
  menu-xdg mplayer2{a} obconf{a} openbox system-tools-backends{a} usermode 
  xdotool{a} 
0 packages upgraded, 44 newly installed, 0 to remove and 5 not upgraded.
Need to get 16,0 MB/17,1 MB of archives.
	After unpacking 53,7 MB will be used.
Do you want to continue? [Y/n/?]

My "guise" script that I use to run alternate instances of software sandboxed from my real name quit working after switching to LXDE. I tracked the issue down to the XDG_CONFIG_HOME environmental variable, which my script was failing to set. With that fixed, my script now works in LXDE as well as Xfce, and presumably should work with some other applications that it was failing to work for in Xfce.

LXDE keeps beeping at me. I haven't figured out why yet. Additionally, there seems to be no battery power level indicator in available in the main LXDE install. I'm going to try to find an indicator to install tomorrow.

My mother came home early today, then Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I all headed out to the hills to pick up bullet shells for several hours. I'm really lost as to what my mother's fascination is with this activity.

Wolf is offended that I used the pronoun pair "he/she" to refer to him in yesterday's weblog entry. Not knowing what pronoun to use at the time, I tried to do the non-offensive thing by using both separated by a slash, but it seems that I can't avoid offending people even that way. This whole gender-based pronoun thing is exceedingly idiotic. There should be one pronoun used to refer to both genders. If that were the case, things like yesterday's mishap wouldn't happen. I apologize Wolf, but I don't know what else I could have done.

Pinentry is a pain in my neck. I really hate the thing. It refuses to allow users to paste in passwords, but GnuPG requires its use, most likely in an attempt to aggravate people and convince them not to encrypt things. Okay, maybe that's not the real intended purpose, but it nearly got me to quit using GnuPG when I first started dealing with Pinentry. In Xfce, Pinentry changed its behavior a bit upon activating GNOME services in the Xfce settings. Pinentry was still stupidly annoying, but much less so. Here in LXDE, Xfce's settings obviously have no effect, so Pinentry went back to being the most painful and obnoxious piece of software installed on my system. I decided to see if it was possible to uninstall it without uninstalling GnuPG, so I did a search to find the package name. I found that there are several versions of Pinentry, so instead of uninstalling it right away, I installed the curses version. After all, what is curses possibly going to do to aggravate me? Figuring that the new version of Pinentry would be a drop-in replacement for the one I'd been dealing with, I purged the GTK+ version. This required me to also remove an old mail client that I haven't used in a while, but has successfully prevented Pinentry from being even mildly annoying. As an experiment, I tried to purge the curses version of Pinentry too, but as expected, several things including GnuPG would have ended up uninstalled as well. Still, this is a major win for me.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My tooth broke again ...

Day 00419: Friday, 2016 April 29

My bad tooth broke further today. This really sucks. It doesn't hurt, but that damage could have probably been prevented if the dentist had an earlier appointment available.

I did some more testing with Pinentry. It seems that the GNOME version of Pinentry doesn't have the annoying anti-paste code that the GTK+ version has. It still steals focus and prevents typing anywhere outside that window, but it's like the version of the Pinentry that was running when GNOME services were running, despite the GNOME version not being installed at that time.

With help from iyanmv in #LXDE, I got the battery monitor plugin set up for the LXDE panel. He said to add this to ~/.config/lxpanel/LXDE/panels/panel and restart:

Plugin {
	type = batt
}

Doing that not only added the battery monitor to the panel, but also added the option to add them via the graphical list of plugins. Why was this not on the list before? I'm so confused. Iyanmv also said that next time that I install a desktop, I'll have better luck if I do it through tasksel, and that tasksel would set the desktop up correctly so I wouldn't end up in a strange state like I apparently did this time. I've also modified my custom session to use LXDE instead of Xfce, so next time that I restart my session, I'll have my Esperanto accented character input capabilities back.

I added tests for two eight more functions in include.d, but I really don't feel like writing more debug code right now. I'd like to move on with actual development. If I'd written the test cases when originally writing the code that it tested, I wouldn't have so much debug code to write right now. Until there's a reason to push a release, I won't cut corners and push one without the proper testing, though if a reason that a release must be made comes along, I might release the code as-is. This release has already had more testing than the last release, and I think that the most problematic component is among those that've been tested. Never mind, I found another bug once I wrote the third test for the day. I'm dealing with the fact that development of include.d didn't start out very organized, so bringing everything up to standard is a bit of an incremental process. It's more important that new code has tests written for it right away than that the old code be dealt with right this moment. I considered creating my new branch to work in that would be used only for code dealing with URI schemes now. I've been planning this branch for a while, and it won't be a main development branch. Instead, it'll be a slow-progress branch that is worked on alongside the main development branch as not to interfere with work on smaller and at-the-time useful branches. However, I quickly realized that this isn't an option yet. While the URI branch is very much going to be created at some point, it can't make progress until my current working branch is merged. This branch made major changes to the base URI class and contains a few new classes that are good for dealing with URIs of a known scheme, which is what the URI branch is all about. I suppose that means that if I get fed up writing debug code and need to work on some URI-parsing code to take a break, that will have to be reason enough to make the next release after all. The current working branch is more of a doozy than it was meant to be, and not much can happen until it is released. That said, if this release is so big, should it not be fully-tested? I should keep working on the debug code as long as I can stand to.

It seems that the beeping that I was hearing yesterday was from WeeChat. It doesn't seem to beep in Xfce. I'm not sure if it's that Xfce's terminal emulator is less supportive of beeps than LXDE's terminal emulator or if it's a deeper difference between the two desktops. While it's nice to have the beeping working better here on LXDE, I've found that my volume keys no longer have an effect. I'll need to look into this tomorrow. I'm starting to recall my problems with LXDE; lack of volume key support was one of the major issues that I had with the desktop.

My mother says that's she's tired and doesn't want us to run a garage sale tomorrow. That's too bad, I was starting to look forward to it.

Vanessa, Cyrus, and I went for a short walk to a park that they knew of. It wasn't far, but once we got there, we headed back. I think that they know the residential area of the city better than I do. Most of my exploration of the town has been in the business district.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.